<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A perfect and exact direction to all those that desire to know the true and just fees of these courts following viz. The fees of all the offices belonging to the Court of Common Pleas, a table of the prothonotaries fees, the fees of the Chancery, according to the table in the office, the ordinance of the Chancery / by Th. Lord Coventry late Lord Keeper of the great seale of England.</title>
            <author>Coventry, Thomas Coventry, Baron, 1578-1640.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1641</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 180 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 79 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A34787</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C6625</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R17316</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12727758</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12727758</idno>
            <idno type="VID">66379</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A34787)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 66379)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 979:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A perfect and exact direction to all those that desire to know the true and just fees of these courts following viz. The fees of all the offices belonging to the Court of Common Pleas, a table of the prothonotaries fees, the fees of the Chancery, according to the table in the office, the ordinance of the Chancery / by Th. Lord Coventry late Lord Keeper of the great seale of England.</title>
                  <author>Coventry, Thomas Coventry, Baron, 1578-1640.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 140 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by R.H. for N. Vavafour, and are to be sold at his shop ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1641.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
                  <note>Index: p. [3]-[6]</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Courts --  Great Britain.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-08</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:1"/>
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:1"/>
                  <p>A PERFECT AND EXACT DIRE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>CTION TO ALL thoſe that deſire to know the true and juſt Fees of theſe Courts following, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>The Fees of all the Offices belonging to the Court of Common Pleas.</p>
                  <p>A Table of the <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Fees.</p>
                  <p>The Fees of the Chancery, according to the Table in the Office.</p>
                  <p>The Ordinance of the Chancery, by <hi>Th.</hi> Lord <hi>Coventry</hi> late Lord Keeper of the great Seale of England.</p>
                  <p>LONDON, Printed by <hi>R. H.</hi> for <hi>N. Vavaſour,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop in the inner Temple. 1641.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:2"/>
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:2"/>
                  <head>A Table of the Offices.</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Uſtos brevium.</hi> fol. 2</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Office. 3</item>
                     <item>The ſecundaries of the <hi>Protho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>notaries.</hi> 4</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the warrants office. ibid.</item>
                     <item>The Phillizers. 5</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Exigenters</hi> office. ibid.</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Chirographers</hi> office. 6</item>
                     <item>The office of the <hi>Kings ſilver.</hi> ibid.</item>
                     <item>The office of the Clark of the Treaſurie. 7</item>
                     <item>The Crier of the Court. 8</item>
                     <item>The keeper of the Treaſurie. 9</item>
                     <item>Inrolling of Fines, Recoveries. ib.</item>
                     <item>A review of a certificate, with an addi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion thereunto, and an anſwer to the Articles. </item>
                     <item>The <hi>Chirographer.</hi> 10</item>
                     <item>The Court keeper. 11</item>
                     <item>The Cryers. ibid.</item>
                     <item>The Porter. 12</item>
                     <item>Aſſociates of the <hi>Niſi prius</hi> at Guildhall. ibid.</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the Errors. ibid.</item>
                     <item>An anſwer to the laſt articles. 13</item>
                     <item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:66379:3"/>The Oath adminiſtred. 16</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cuſtos brevium</hi> Fees. 18</item>
                     <item>Fees for the Clarkes of the <hi>Cuſtos bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium.</hi> 22</item>
                     <item>Fees allowed to the Bagbearer by the <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtos brevium.</hi> 23</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> fees. 24</item>
                     <item>Fees for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rits. 31</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Clarkes fees. 34</item>
                     <item>Fees for the Clark of the inrollments. 36</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chirographers</hi> fees. 37</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chirographers</hi> Clarkes fees. 39</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the Treaſurie. 40</item>
                     <item>For the keeping the Treaſurie. ibid.</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the <hi>Kings ſilver.</hi> 42</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Phillizers</hi> Fees. ibid.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Exigenters</hi> Fees. 45</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the Jurors. 48</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the <hi>Eſſoines.</hi> 49</item>
                     <item>Outlawrie Office. 50</item>
                     <item>Fees or the Seale. 52</item>
                     <item>Fees for the Marſhall. ibid.</item>
                     <item>Criers Fees. 54</item>
                     <item>Fees for the keeper of the Court. 55</item>
                     <item>Fees of the Clarke of the inrolments. ib.</item>
                     <item>Fees for the Porter of the Court. 56</item>
                     <item>Alienation Office. 57</item>
                     <item>Fees taken by the Maſter of the Chancery 57</item>
                     <item>Fees taken for the Compoſitions. 58</item>
                     <item>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nder Sherife of Middleſex. 60</item>
                     <item>Warden of the Fleet. 61</item>
                     <item>The Jurors preſentment. 66</item>
                     <item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:66379:3"/>Judges Fees. 68</item>
                     <item>Serjeants Fees. 70</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cuſtos brevium</hi> Fees. 71</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Office. 73</item>
                     <item>Secundaries Fees. 74</item>
                     <item>Clark of the Warrants office. ibid.</item>
                     <item>In the <hi>Phillizers</hi> office. 75</item>
                     <item>In the <hi>Exigenters</hi> office. 76</item>
                     <item>In the <hi>Chirographers</hi> office. ibid.</item>
                     <item>In the office of the <hi>Kings ſilver.</hi> 77</item>
                     <item>In the office of the Clark of the Treaſurie. 78</item>
                     <item>The Criers Fees. 80</item>
                     <item>In the office of the keeper of the Treaſurie. 81</item>
                     <item>In the Outlawrie office. 82</item>
                     <item>The <hi>Proclamators</hi> Fees. 83</item>
                     <item>Clarke of the <hi>Juries.</hi> ibid.</item>
                     <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Eſſoines.</hi> 84</item>
                     <item>The Court keeper. ibid.</item>
                     <item>The Porters Fees. 85</item>
                     <item>The Clark of the <hi>Errors</hi> Fees. 86</item>
                     <item>The Clark of the <hi>Inrolment</hi> Fees. 87</item>
                     <item>The Attornies Fees. 88</item>
                     <item>The Lo: chiefe Iuſtice his Fees. 90</item>
                     <item>Fees belonging to the Judges which doe the buſineſſe. 91</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Divident</hi> Fees. 93</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Puiſne</hi> Judges Fees. 94</item>
                     <item>Fees due to the Lord chiefe Juſtice his Clarks. 96</item>
                     <item>Lord chiefe Justice his Fees. 99</item>
                     <item>The Fees due to ſuch Iudges which doe
<pb facs="tcp:66379:4"/>
the buſineſſe. 10<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Divident</hi> Fees. 103</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Puiſne</hi> Iudges Fees. ibid.</item>
                     <item>A Table of the due fees of the <hi>Protho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>notaries.</hi> 109</item>
                     <item>Fees belonging to the Chancery. 127</item>
                     <item>Ordinances in the Chancery. 134</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div type="part">
                  <pb n="1" facs="tcp:66379:4"/>
                  <opener>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>
                           <hi>TERMINO HILLARII,</hi> Viceſimo primo Iacobi Regis. 1623.</date>
                     </dateline>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ccording to your honours dire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, having (ſince the time of your Lordſhips pleaſure made knowne unto us) received from your Lordſhips, divers Bills, and Notes of the Fees claimed by ſeverall Officers in the right of their Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, in his highneſſe Court of Common pleas at Weſtminſter, and thereby, and by Oath to bee adminiſtred unto us, concerning your honours pleaſures and intendments to be performed, whether all the Fees and Summes of money ſet downe and claimed reſpectively in the ſaid Bills and Notes, have been paid ſince the thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth yeare of the late Queene <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> or which, or how many thereof, or what other have been advanced, encreaſed, or taken ſince the ſaid thirtieth yeare, in the ſaid Offices, in the ſaid Court of Common Pleas.</p>
                  <p>Upon peruſall of the ſaid Bills and Notes, and conſideration of the Fees now claimed, and
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:66379:5"/>
taken upon our ſeverall knowledges, and upon credible report, we finde ſome for to be advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced, encreaſed, raiſed, and taken ſince the ſaid thirtieth yeare. And therefore in all humble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe, We have briefly ſet downe under the title of every Office, ſuch as we at this preſent re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively know to have been ſo advanced, en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed, raiſed, and taken with ſome grounds and reaſons of the advancing, encreaſing, rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, and taking thereof, delivered by them, to their ſeverall Notes of Fees annexed.</p>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of <hi>Cuſtos Brevium.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere is, and hath been taken by the Clarks there, more than heretofore was taken and claimed by them upon Fines, upon the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourne of Writs of Covenant under colour of Deputations from the Sheriffes, and now is claimed by them for keeping the parts of the Fine. xii. d.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for filing every Writ after two Termes, for every Terme after, xx. d. Whereas the ſaid Fee of xx. d. was accepted for filing of any Writ at any time within the yeare.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there is taken by the ſaid Clarkes, for filing of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Writs of Entrie, Summons, and Seiſin upon common Recoveries, xii. d. where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ormerly iiii. d. was taken as their Maſter<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Fee for a <hi>poſt diem.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="3" facs="tcp:66379:5"/>
                     <head>In the <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THere hath beene taken for the moſt part of ſeven yeares paſt, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on every judgement in perſonall, and mixt Actions, over and above the ii. s. in the Bill of their Fees mentioned, and more than was formerly paid, xii. d. being for aſſeſſing of Coſts for the Judges as is affirmed.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there hath been taken by the ſpace of foure yeares laſt paſt, or there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts, xviii. d. upon every Writ of Entrie, Summons, and Seiſin upon common Recoveries, which was not formerly paid.</p>
                     <p>There hath been alſo taken by the ſpace of twelve or fourteene yeares laſt paſt, by them iiii. s. upon the reverſall of every Outlawrie, not formerly ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken.</p>
                     <p>They have alſo received and taken for divers yeares laſt paſt, the ſumme of ix. s. iiii. d. upon every prohibition granted in Court, but whether the ſame bee a due, and ancient Fee, we doe not certainly know: All which Fees ſo taken (as we conceive) are up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the reaſons expreſſed in a Note, which we have annexed to their Bill of Fees.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="4" facs="tcp:66379:6"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Secondaries</hi> of the ſaid Prothonotaries.</head>
                     <p>THere hath been taken by the ſpace of ten yeares laſt paſt, or therea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouts, xii. d. upon every com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Recovery drawne at the Bar, more than formerly hath been taken, which the Secondaries affirme to have beene taken in reſpect the Demaundants in ſuch Recoveries have not appeared at the Bar in perſon.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>Clarke of the <hi>Warrants</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THere is taken upon every Fine more than formerly iiii. d. for a Warrant of Attourney, and char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged out of the Attournies Fee by order of the Judges made 14. <hi>Iac. Reg.</hi> certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied by this Officer to his Lordſhip.</p>
                     <p>There was alſo taken by the Deputy of this Officer for the ſpace of three or foure yeares, and untill within one yeare laſt paſt, upon every Fine xviii. d. which was not formerly paid to that Officer, being ſo taken (as is pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed) for the retourne of the Writ of
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:66379:6"/>
Covenant, and hath ſince been taken by Maſter <hi>Thomas Iackman,</hi> Clarke of the Inrollments of Fines and Recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, upon the reaſons annexed to the Bill of Fees of the Clarke of the War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Phillizers.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere is taken iiii. d. upon every Cap. and viii. d. upon every ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance of the Defendant, more then was taken before 14. <hi>Iac. Reg.</hi> which is taken by vertue of an Order made upon the reaſons expreſſed in the ſame Order to their Bill of Fees an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nexed.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Exigenters</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THere hath been taken ever ſince 31. <hi>Eliz.</hi> upon every Exigent more than was formerly taken 1. d. which was ſo taken in reſpect of the length of the Proclamation.</p>
                     <p>And there hath beene alſo taken by the ſpace of three yeares paſt, i. d. more upon every Exigent, upon ſuch reaſons as are offered to your Lordſhips conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derations, in their Certificate of Fees.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="6" facs="tcp:66379:7"/>
                     <head>In the <hi>Chirographers</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THere is taken by the Clarkes of the ſaid Office for writing the Chirograph of every Fine ii. s. vi. d. which ſince 30. <hi>Eliz.</hi> was but xvi. d. which ſumme of ii. s. vi. d. upon reaſons ſhewed to divers ancient Attournies by the Clarkes of the ſaid Office about ſeventeene yeares ſince, was aſſented unto by the ſaid Attournies, bee the Fine long, or ſhort.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of the <hi>Kings ſilver.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere is encreaſed, and taken by the ſpace of thirteene yeares laſt paſt, or thereabouts iiii. d. upon every Fine by Order made in 8. <hi>Iac. Reg.</hi> annexed to their Bill of Fees.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there hath been taken and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed iiii. d. lately, within five yeares ſince the time laſt above mentioned for every ſeverall Cap. of a Fine, having more Cap. than one, which was not for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly taken.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for the time of thirteene yeares laſt paſt, there hath been taken for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:66379:7"/>
Fine by ſpeciall Commiſſion, iiii. d. which is an encreaſed Fee.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there hath beene taken ſince 8. <hi>Iac. Reg</hi> vi. d. for every Fine brought into the Office after the end of every Terme, not formerly taken.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there hath been taken the ſumm of viii. d. upon every Fine in the We<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſterne Circuits, more than upon Fines in other Counties, which grew to bee taken about 34. <hi>Eliz.</hi> by colour of de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putations from the Sheriffes of the Weſterne Circuits upon the reaſons annexed to his Bill of Fees, moſt of which ſaid Fees were raiſed, and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed in the time when Rich. <hi>Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers,</hi> Was that Officer.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of the <hi>Clarke</hi> of the <hi>Treaſury.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere is of late taken iiii. s. for the ſearch of every Terme after ten yeares, the olde and ancient Fee being but iii. s. iiii. d.</p>
                     <p>There is claimed iii. s. for turning the key of the Treaſury after the Terme, whereas there is but xii. d. due.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there is claimed by his ſaid Bill iiii. d. for ſearch of a Record under ten yeares untill three yeares, no ſuch Fee being due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="8" facs="tcp:66379:8"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Cryers</hi> of the Court.</head>
                     <p>THere is taken by them ii. s. the Fee being but xii. d. for calling every Jury at the Bar, when they fill not.</p>
                     <p>Alſo they take xvi. s. for keeping eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Jury during the ſitting of the Court, and xxx. s. for keeping them all night, The ancient Fee for the firſt (as wee underſtand) being but iiii. s. and the other viii. s. and no more.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there is taken by them for ſwea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring an Attourney in Court ii. s. more than their ancient Fee, (being iiii. s.) as we are credibly informed.</p>
                     <p>Alſo they take upon every Baile ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken in Court xii. d. there being no Fee due, that we know, or have heard of.</p>
                     <p>Alſo they take iiii. s. upon every <hi>Niſi prius</hi> before my Lord chiefe Juſtice of the common Pleas at Weſtminſter, there being no ſuch Fee due to our knowledge.</p>
                     <p>Alſo they demand iiii. s. iiii. d. upon every Wager in Law, there being but ii. s. due, as we have heard.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="9" facs="tcp:66379:8"/>
                     <head>In the Office of the <hi>Keeper</hi> of the <hi>Treaſury.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere is claimed in his Bill for a Search after three yeares, untill ten yeares iiii. d. there being no ſuch Fee due.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for a Roll carried into the Court, vi. d. there being no ſuch Fee to our knowledge, other than for car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying a Roll of the precedent Terme.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for every Jury at the Barre ii. s. vi. d. there being only xii. d. due, and formerly paid, as we have heard.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for every <hi>Niſi prius</hi> tryed in Middleſex ii. s. vi. d. there being but xii. d. due.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for a copy of a Precipe xviii. d. there being none ever heard of.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for the acknowledging of a Fine iiii. d. there being nothing due.</p>
                     <p>Alſo for the key xviii. d. xii. d. being due, and no more.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="10" facs="tcp:66379:9"/>
                     <head>In the Office of <hi>Inrolling,</hi> and <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>emplifying</hi> of Fines and Recoveries.</head>
                     <p>THe Fees challenged by this Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer (as we conceive) doe differ from the Fees limited by the Sta. 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi> unto which Stat. we refer our ſelves.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Chirographer.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>A review of our former Certificate, with an addition thereto, and an anſwer to the Articles lately de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered unto us by your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>THere is taken by the Clarke of the ſaid Office, for writing of the Chirograph of every Fine, ii. s. vi. d. for which ſince 30. <hi>Eliz.</hi> was only paid xii. d. but about <hi>Anno</hi> 4. <hi>Iac. Reg.</hi> they did procure the conſent of divers ancient Attournies in writing under their hands, for the increaſe thereof, to make the xii. d. ii. s. vi. d. be the Chiro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graph
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:66379:9"/>
long or ſhort, upon promiſe ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver to demand any more, yet ſince they exact, and take more according to the length.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Court-keeper.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>VVHereas this Officer requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reth ix. s. vi. d. for a Wager of Law, his due being only xxii. d. the reſt is to be divided amongſt the Cryers, Wagermen, and other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Cryers.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>VVHereas it hath been former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly certified that ii. s. is due to theſe Officers for a Wager of Law, upon better conſideration wee finde iiii. s. is due unto them out of the ix. s. vi. d.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="12" facs="tcp:66379:10"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Porter.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>HEE taketh ii. s. vi. d. for every triall at the Barre, his Fee being but xii. d. and for a <hi>Niſi prius</hi> xii. d. his due being but vi. d.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Aſſociats</hi> of the <hi>Niſi prius</hi> at <hi>Guildhall.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THis Officer taketh xii. d. for re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourne of the Plaintifes <hi>Poſtea,</hi> and ii. s. for retourne of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſendants <hi>Postea,</hi> and for the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants Verdict ii. s. which are new en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed Fees ſince 30. <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Clarke</hi> of the Errors.</head>
                     <p>THis Officer taketh for a <hi>Superſid. de non moleſtando</hi> iii. s. there being but ii. s. anciently due, and ii. s. for making the Record.</p>
                     <p>He taketh alſo ii. s. iiii. d. for a <hi>Non<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuite</hi> in a Writ of Error, being not due, nor paid ſince 30. <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="13" facs="tcp:66379:10"/>
                     <head>An anſwer to the laſt <hi>Articles.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Prothonotaries take by the Sheete, and not by the Roll, all the time of our remembrance, eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſheete containing twelve lines, and every line ten words, according as they have certified in their note of Fees.</p>
                     <p>They take for the certifying the firſt cauſe vi. s. and for every other cauſe ii. s. and ſo have anciently done.</p>
                     <p>The chiefe Juſtice his Fee for allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of a Writ of Error was but xvii. s. vi. d. being upon meane Proces and ſingle judgement, and if it exceed to Ex. <hi>poſt.</hi> Cap. and <hi>Scire fac.</hi> xxxv. s. and for the <hi>Superſid.</hi> ii. s. and no more, and now is taken for allowance upon meane Proces xx. s. and for a <hi>Superſid.</hi> iiii. s.</p>
                     <p>The ancient Fee of a Cap. <hi>Vtlegat.</hi> ſpeciall, is ii. s. iiii. d. and a generall Writ x. d. if more be taken, it is to the writer of the Writ for expedition given by the Attourney as a gratuity.</p>
                     <p>We doe not know of any Fees taken by Bills of Parcels, and at Etiam, more than hath been formerly taken <hi>Anno 30. Eliz.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="14" facs="tcp:66379:11"/>The Judges take only iiii. s. for ſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of a Writ of priviledge, which Fee is, and hath been ancient for any thing we know, and the like for ſigning of a <hi>Procedendo.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The ancient Fee for reverſing of an Outlawry in a Judges Chamber wee know not, but there hath been taken for the Judge ix. s. viii. d. and xii. d. to his man, and being reverſed in Court, iiii. s. as is formerly certified.</p>
                     <p>There is now paid to the Judges horſekeeper for triall of every cauſe at Guildhall xii. d. and upon triall at the Barre ii. s. to each of the Judges foot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloath-keeper, and in many Circuits upon every triall, for keeping the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries ii. s. for every Jury, there being on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly due xii. d. which was formerly al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed and paid to the Sheriffes Bai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liffes for keeping of the Juries.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there hath been taken in ſome Circuits upon triall of every <hi>Niſiprius,</hi> wherein a private verdict hath beene given (as Fees for the ſame verdict) to the Judges Marſhall for all manner of Fees to all Officers xv. s. viii. d. but now of late the Judges ſervants and of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers in ſome Circuits doe demand, and take x. s. more, not anciently taken.</p>
                     <p>The ancient Fee in a Prohibition, was ix. s. iiii. d. for every witneſſe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced to prove a ſuggeſtion out of
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:66379:11"/>
Court, and in Court. iiii. s.</p>
                     <p>It is anſwered in the former Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate, the ancient Fee for ſwearing an Attourney in Court, was ii. s. to the Boxe, and now xx. s. is taken.</p>
                     <p>Every Attourney paies Tear<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ely, of ought to pay iiii. d. to the Clarke of the Warrants, who is appointed to pay the ſame to the Judges, and is by them di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtributed to the poore, as is affirmed.</p>
                     <p>There hath been, and is taken for the Boxe upon every ſatisfaction for a Judgement being under 100. li. vi. d. if 100. l. xii. d. and for every 100. li. ſo <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ateably, and the like for a confeſſion, and vi. d. upon a Baile, and every common Recovery.</p>
                     <list>
                        <head>Subſcribed thus</head>
                        <item>Hen: Plombe.</item>
                        <item>Sy: Wiſeman.</item>
                        <item>Anth: Langſton.</item>
                        <item>Geo: Needler.</item>
                        <item>Will: Brag.</item>
                        <item>Ioh: Nichols.</item>
                        <item>Geo: Cooe.</item>
                        <item>Will: Carefield.</item>
                        <item>Peter-Bird.</item>
                        <item>Tho: Agar.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="16" facs="tcp:66379:12"/>
                     <head>
                        <hi>The Oath adminiſtred touching the Court of Common Pleas to the inqueſt of Attournies in Feb.</hi> 1627.</head>
                     <p>YOu ſhall well and truly accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to your knowledge, give true information to his Majeſties Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for inquiry after exacted Fees, and innovated Offices, what Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices and places were uſually held, kept, and executed in the tenth yeare of the raigne of the late Queene <hi>Eliz.</hi> or at any time ſince in the Court of Common Pleas.</p>
                     <p>You ſhall well and truly, according to your knowledge, give true informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, what offices and places have been ſince the eleventh yeare of the ſaid late Queene, invented, innovated, deſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, ordained, or erected by Judges, Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices, or other chiefe Officers in the ſame Court, and not granted, or men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned to be granted by Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents under the great Seale of Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</p>
                     <p>And what Rewards, Fees, Summe, and Summes of money were in the ſaid eleventh yeare of the ſaid late Queene <hi>Eliz.</hi> or at any time ſince,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:66379:12"/>
uſually, or accuſtomably taken, recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, or had by the Judges, Counſellors, Practiſers, or Officers, or their Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, or other Miniſters, Clarkes, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſters, or Attournies in the ſame Court.</p>
                     <p>And what Rewards, Fees, and Summes of money under colour, or by name of Fees, Rewards, Gratuities, Clarkes paines, <hi>poſt Term. post diems,</hi> Expedition, or the like, have ſince the ſaid eleventh yeare of the ſaid late Queene <hi>Eliz.</hi> been ſet, impoſed, raiſed, advanced, encreaſed, incroached, or taken into the ſaid Court, and of the particularities, grounds, or reaſons thereof, with all other incidents, and circumſtances touching the promiſſes.</p>
                     <p>And whether have you any Rolls, Warrants, Records, Orders, Tables, Bookes, Entries, or other Notes, or Writings in your cuſtody, whereby the truth in the premiſſes may be the better found out, and diſcovered.</p>
                     <p>Or doe you know where any ſuch Rolls, Warrants, Records, Tables, Orders, Bookes, Entries, of other Notes are, or have been, or with whom they now remaine, So help you God.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Ex officio per Edm. wodax, cler. commiſſ.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="18" facs="tcp:66379:13"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Cuſtos Brevium</hi> his Fees.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Theſe Fees following, are the Fees which are taken by Sir <hi>Thomas Spencer, Cuſtos Brevium</hi> of his Maieſties Court of Common Pleas, and his Clarkes in right of his ſaid Office, and as they were taken <hi>11. Eliz.</hi> by the then Maſter of the ſaid Office, and his Clarkes.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> for filing any Writ, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Record, comming after the day of the retourne thereof, except Writs of priuiledge <hi>de veneundo, &amp; redeundo,</hi> and alſo Writs of priviledge called <hi>propr.</hi> or <hi>poſt diems.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For filing any Writ, or other Record (except before excepted) com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming after the Terme wherein it was retournable, called a <hi>poſt diem Term.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xx. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="19" facs="tcp:66379:13"/>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For filing any Writ, or other Record comming after two Termes, called <hi>poſt Termin.</hi> for every Terme af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter xx. d. a piece, except Exigents, and Outlawries, which pay but only xx. d. a <hi>poſt Termin.</hi> be they never ſo long, after <hi>quia pro Dom. Rege,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xx. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the ſearch of any Writ, or other Record, being under five yeares, for every retourne v. d. except ſuch Writs as where the whole Terme is uſed to be filed together, which pay only v. d. a Terme, out of which they allow to the Bag-bearer<note place="margin">v. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the ſearch of any Writ, or other Record of five yeares antiquity, and under ten yeares called a Temple ſearch, for the firſt retourne ii. s. ix. d. and for every retourne after v. d. ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept ſuch Writs, as where the whole Terme is uſed to be filed together, which pay likewiſe for the firſt Terme, ii. s. ix. d. and for every Terme after v. d. out of which Temple ſearch there is al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed to the Clarke iiii. d. and to the Bag-bearer v. d.<note place="margin">ii. s. ix. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> for the ſearch of any Writ, or other Record of ten yeares antiquity and upwards, called a Weſtm. ſearch for the firſt Terme ix. s. ix. d. and for every Terme after v. d. except ſuch Writs as where the whole Terme is uſed to be filed together, which pay
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:66379:14"/>
only v. d. a Terme, out of which Weſt. ſearch there is allowed to the Clarkes i. s. i. d. and to the Bag-bearer<note place="margin">ix. s. ix. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the allowance of every Writ of <hi>Certiorari,</hi> directed to the <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtos Brevium,</hi> xiiii. s. ix. d. whereof is al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed to the Clarke ii. s. viii. d. and for certifying thereof, <hi>Secundum longitudi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nem,</hi> and according to reaſon,<note place="margin">xiiii. s. ix. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the allowance of every Exemplification made out of the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of any Writ, or Writs, or other Record, v. s. iiii. d. and to the Clarke for writing and examining thereof <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundum longitudinem,</hi> and according to reaſon,<note place="margin">v. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the carrying of any Writ, or other Record to the Court for a re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſall, or any other occaſion ii. s. ix. d. whereof allowed to the Clarkes iiii. d. and to the Bag-bearer,<note place="margin">ii. s. ix. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For filing any common Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very, Writ, <hi>ſuper diſſeiſinam in le poſt,</hi> xii. d. whereof allowed to the Clarkes, viii. d. for entring the ſame into a book for that purpoſe,<note place="margin">xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For entring a Fine with the <hi>Cuſtos Brevium,</hi> by vertue of the Stat. 5. H. 4. <hi>cap.</hi> 14. in which Stat. that is called the accuſtomed old Fee,<note place="margin">xxii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> To the Clarke of the ſame Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice (<hi>ab antiquo</hi>) who enters the ſame,<note place="margin">ii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="21" facs="tcp:66379:14"/>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> Upon the making of the Stat. 4. H. 7. <hi>cap.</hi> 24. the <hi>Cuſtos Brevium</hi> was allowed by the Court for carrying, and recarrying of every Fine levied according to that Stat. Weſtmin. to the Chirographer to proclaime foure Termes,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For keeping three parts of the Record of every Fine conſiſting of five parts, iiii. d. a piece,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>In tot.</hi> for every Fine iii. s. viii. d. whereof the Maſter hath ii. s. vi. d. and xiiii. d. is allowed to the Clarkes,<note place="margin">iii. s. viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the amendment of every Writ, or other Record <hi>per Warrant. Cur.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xx. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every <hi>Non eſt factum</hi> plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded in Court,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Sheriffes bundle of Writs retournable of the precedent Terme, and comming before Eſſoine day of the ſecond retourne of the new Terme.<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Tho: Spencer.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="22" facs="tcp:66379:15"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>The uſuall Fees allowed by the <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtos Brevium</hi> to the Clarkes of his Office.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For every Temple ſearch,<note place="margin">iiii. d. ii. s. i. d.</note> 
                        <hi>Item,</hi> Out of every Weſtm. ſearch, <hi>Item,</hi> To the Clarkes out of the al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance of every <hi>Certiorari</hi> ii. s. viii. d. and for certifying the ſame, <hi>ſecundum longitudinem,</hi> and according to reaſon,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> To the Clarke for writing and examining of every Exemplification, <hi>ſecundum longitudinem.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> To the Clarke for any Writ, or other Record carried into the Court.<note place="margin">iiii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For entring a common Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Writ <hi>ſuper diſſeiſinam in le poſt,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Fine paſſing in the Office,<note place="margin">xiiii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For entring into a Booke every <hi>Recipiatur</hi> comming under a Judges hand, or by order of Court,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every note of Jurors names for the Clarke of the Juries to make further Proces by,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every note of an Exigent for the Clarke of the Outlawries to make further Proces by,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="23" facs="tcp:66379:15"/>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the ſearch of any Booke of Entries, of any Writs for every Terme,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For the copie of any Writ, or other Record for every Sheete.<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Geo: Venables.<lb/>
Alex: Thurley.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>The uſuall Fees allowed by the <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtos Brevium,</hi> to the Bag-bearer of the Office, being alwaies the common Vouchee of the Court.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For every ſearch under five yeares,<note place="margin">i. d. v. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Temple ſearch,</p>
                     <p>For every Weſtm. ſearch,</p>
                     <p>For any Writ, or other Record car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried into the Court,<note place="margin">v. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every common Recovery ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in Court (being the common Vou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chee) iiii. d. a piece,<note place="margin">iiii. d. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Attorney ſworn in Court,</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="24" facs="tcp:66379:16"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Theſe Fees are due, and belonging to the three <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> of the common Pleas.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For entring every com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Declaration, common Plea in Barre, wherein no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Freehold is pleaded, common Replication, and common Rejoynder in actions perſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nall,<note place="margin">xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of every ſpeciall Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, ſpeciall Plea in Barre, or abate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Freehold, Replication, or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joynder, and Pleas ſubſequent in acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons perſonall not exceeding three ſheetes, every ſheete containing twelve lines, and every line ten words at the leaſt,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For every Declaration in actions up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Caſe <hi>Ejectione firme,</hi> Annuity, Accompt, Covenant, Conſpiracy, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceip<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>, Partition, Pleg. <hi>Acquietand.</hi>
                        <pb n="25" facs="tcp:66379:16"/>
Debt upon Stat. Plaint in Aſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ize, and the like ſpeciall actions, and in all re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all, mixt and popular, if the Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or Plaint exceed not three ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Barre Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication, Rejoynder, and Pleas ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequent in every of the actions laſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove mentioned, and in the like acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Obligation, Indenture, Record, retourne of Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate, or the like entred <hi>in haec verba</hi> not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For recording of every apparance by the Court,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Recogni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zance without condition, challenge to the Sheriffes, or Coroners, or to the Array, or other ſpeciall averments,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Recognizance with the condition,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every judgement in debt deti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue, and treſpaſſe without a <hi>Tales,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Adjourne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every judgement, with a <hi>Tales</hi> beſides the Fee aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Remanet and judgement for Coſts given to the Defendant by the Stat. beſides the Fee aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="26" facs="tcp:66379:17"/>For every judgement in all other actions, as well perſonall as mixt Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibitions, and the like,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſatisfaction <hi>Recordatur,</hi> Diſcontinuance, <hi>Retraxit,</hi> Relinquiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, <hi>Nolle proſocuti,</hi> or the like in perſonall actions,<note place="margin">ii. s. iii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And in reall actions,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of a ſingle Recovery, and the Writ of ſeiſin thereupon,<note place="margin">x. s. vi. d iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Voucher more,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every <hi>Mittimus,</hi> or <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem</hi> for a common Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery,<note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of a Summons at Bar for a common Recovery, and a Writ of Summons, <hi>ad warrantizand.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iv. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of a <hi>Certiorari,</hi> to cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie a Warrant of Attourney for the Tenant, or Vouchee,<note place="margin">iiii. s. vi. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if for both,</p>
                     <p>For every common Voucher ſent to the common Pleas to ſummon the Vou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chee, if the Record be not above three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>The like Fees are paid when the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord is to be remitted after the Vou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cher determined,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every ſpeciall Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict, whereupon a <hi>Cur. adviſare vult</hi> is entred, being not above three ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="27" facs="tcp:66379:17"/>For the entrie of every generall Verdict, with a <hi>Cur. adv<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ſare vult,</hi> without a <hi>Tales,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And with a <hi>Tales,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every <hi>Remittimus</hi> of debt and damages,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Information upon a penall Law, not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every ſurmiſe for a Prohibition to be granted, not exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For entring of every <hi>Audita querela,</hi> not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Oath of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry witneſſe to prove the ſurmiſe in a Prohibition, or <hi>Audita quer.</hi> brought by an Infant, and the entrie of the proofes <hi>de morte,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>vita viri</hi> in dow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, and the like actions and ſuits,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For releaſing of any default in any reall action,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For damages cleere in any action where damage is given, if the damage given amount unto five markes, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove ii. s. in the pound,<note place="margin">ii. s. o</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If under five markes,</p>
                     <p>For examining any Record of <hi>Niſi prius,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="28" facs="tcp:66379:18"/>For making the Record for triall of any iſſue in any of the Counties Pala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine, for the firſt three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For the exemplification of every Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord, not exceeding ſixe ſheetes,<note place="margin">v. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of Seiſin in dower, and dying ſeiſed, if the retourne of the ſeiſin exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">iiii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For entring the default upon treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſe in waſte, <hi>Quare impedit,</hi> if the Count, or title doe not exceed three ſheetes,<note place="margin">vi. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of a <hi>Quo warranto,</hi> not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Plea there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon according to the ſame rate,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Plea in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt, pleaded before Auditors, if it be not above three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Summons, ſeverances and aide <hi>de prior,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For admiſſion of an Infant to his Guardian, or <hi>Procheine Amie,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if by Commiſſion,</p>
                     <p>For entring the Writs of <hi>Exemp. de non. ponend. in Iurat. &amp; Paten. de li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertatibus allocandis &amp; protectionibus,</hi>
                        <pb n="29" facs="tcp:66379:18"/>
Cognizance of Pleas, and the like, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the rates aforeſaid, if it ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of a Defendants diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge upon a <hi>cap. pro fine,</hi> or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the like upon a reſcous retourn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and admitted to his Fine,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For traverſing the reſcous and iſſue thereon,<note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of the allowance of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry generall and ſpeciall Pardon of Outlawrie before judgement, and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,<note place="margin">v. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of a <hi>Dies dat,</hi> in debt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue, and treſpaſſe,<note place="margin">xii. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And in all other actions,</p>
                     <p>For entring of a receipt of a Feme covert, Tenant in taile, Leaſſec for yeares, or the like,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of a Plea, if it exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>And if the receipt be by Writ, then more for entring the Writ,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring of an Aſſize deliver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in Court of the common Pleas, by the Juſtices of the Aſſize, to be inrolled for every ſheete,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if the Aſſize come into the Court by <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ertiorari,</hi> then more for en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tring the ſame,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="30" facs="tcp:66379:19"/>For entring of every Abridgement of the Demaund. in dower, waſte, and the like,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every <hi>Pone</hi> to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move a Plea by Writ out of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Court there holden by Juſtices, and for retourne of the <hi>Pone,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring of any Record ſent into the Court by <hi>Mittimus,</hi> or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, and for entring of every <hi>Rege in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conſulto,</hi> or the like, if it exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For the entring of every <hi>Certiorari</hi> of Baſtardy, certified by the Biſhop, the awarding of the Writ, and judgement thereupon,<note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entrie of the Licence of the Court to purchaſe a new Writ by jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies of accompt,</p>
                     <p>For entring of every Originall Writ delivered of Record in reall and mixt actions,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="31" facs="tcp:66379:19"/>
                     <head>Fees for <hi>Writs.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>FOr every Writ of Prohibition, or Conſulation, not exceeding foure ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For every Withernam, <hi>Return. Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bend.</hi> after appearance, ſecond delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, Writ of priviledge, <hi>Habeas cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus, Procedendo, Certiorari,</hi> Summons, and reſummons <hi>pet. cap. ven. fac. Scir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fac. Elegit, Extent. Superſid. Subpen.</hi> Writ to the Biſhop, Attachment, <hi>Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtring. Iur. Habeas corp. &amp; diſtring. in Aſſ. &amp; Attinct.</hi> and the like, <hi>haberi fac. ſeiſin. haberi fac. poſſ.</hi> Writ of View, <hi>Mittimus, Indempnitat. nominis,</hi> and every other ſpeciall Writ,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring of every ſuch other Writ which requires an entring, not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Teſtat. ſcir. fac. &amp; Teſtat. fieri fac. diſtring. ad deliberand.</hi> and Writs to inquire of damages of Treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſe, and Replevin,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Writs to enquire of damages in Covenant, Ejectment, Actions upon the Caſe, and the like,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Cap. pro fine,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="32" facs="tcp:66379:20"/>For the Exigent of a <hi>Cap. pro fine.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring the retourne in every Writ in the Prothonotaries Roll, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then the retourne, <hi>Non eſt invent.</hi> and upon the <hi>Scire fac. nulla hab. bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na,</hi> whereupon any further proceſſe is awarded, not exceeding foure ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For the entring of every Writ of pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledge, or <hi>Habeas corpus,</hi> with the baile for one cauſe,<note place="margin">vi. s. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every cauſe more,</p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every <hi>Mittimus die &amp; cauſa,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every reverſall upon an Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawry, for default of Proclamation, with one name, and the baile upon a <hi>Nolle proſecuti,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">v. s. iv. d ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every name more,</p>
                     <p>For every reverſall, for every inſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient Exigent, or retourne for one name,<note place="margin">8. s. iv. d ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every name more,</p>
                     <p>The Fees aboveſaid, are the Fees which were uſually and accuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mably taken in my Office of chief Prothonotarie of the Court of common Pleas at Weſtminſter, <hi>in Ann. 32, &amp; 33. Eliz. nup. Reg. Angl.</hi> in which yeare I was admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to the ſaid Office, and as I verily thinke, the ancient Fees of the Court.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Brownelowe.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="33" facs="tcp:66379:20"/>
                     <p>
                        <hi>IN Anno xvi, Iac. Reg.</hi> I came to my Office of ſecond Prothonotary of the ſaid Court of common Pleas, and the Fees before mentioned were the Fees which uſually and accuſtoma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly then were taken, and I doe verily thinke them to be the ancient Fees of the Court, belonging to my Office.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Gulſon.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <p>THe Fees before recited, are the Fees which were uſually and accuſtomably taken in my ſaid Office of third Prothonotary of the ſaid Court, <hi>in Anno 3. Car. Reg.</hi> in which inſtant yeare I was admitted to the ſaid Office, and I verily thinke they are the ancient Fees of the ſaid Court.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Moyle.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="34" facs="tcp:66379:21"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Prothonotaries Clarks</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For the copies of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Declarations and Pleas, for every ſheete written as aforeſaid,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete in reall and mixt Actions, and actions upon any Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, and the like,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing every ſpeciall Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and Plea, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every continuance every Terme, of every Iſſue, Writ, Impurlance, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>murrer, ſpeciall Verdict, or Adjourn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For exemplifying of every Recovery, with a double Voucher,<note place="margin">vi. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Voucher more,</p>
                     <p>For exemplifying of any Record, not exceeding eight ſheetes,<note place="margin">v. s. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For drawing every extraordinary long Writ, after the rate for every ſheete of,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie thereof, if it ſhall ſo require, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copie of a judgement, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every Writ, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourne thereof into the Prothonotaries
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:66379:21"/>
remembrance, for the drawing up of a judgement, if it exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">vi. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete above,</p>
                     <p>For entring every common Rule in the Bill of Pleas, or common remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring and ingroſſing of every Summons for a Recovery, and for ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of the Writ of Summons,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entrie of every <hi>Mittimus,</hi> or <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem,</hi> for a Recovery,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ingroſſing of every <hi>Niſi prius,</hi> after the rate of iiii. d. for every ſheete,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring every <hi>Teſtat. Fieri fac. &amp; Scire fac.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="36" facs="tcp:66379:22"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>The Fees of the <hi>Clarke</hi> of the <hi>Inrollments, Warrants,</hi> and <hi>Eſtreats</hi> in the common Pleas, as are now, and have been taken theſe two and thirty yeares, and as I conceive were taken ever ſince <hi>31. Eliz.</hi> ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the Fee hereafter mentioned, allowed <hi>per ordin. Cur.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>EVery Inrollment containing a ſide of a Roll,<note place="margin">v. s, x. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Of a full Roll,</p>
                     <p>And ſo according to that rate,</p>
                     <p>Every Warrant of Attourney <hi>in deb. tranſg. &amp; deten.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>The Sheriffes Warrants,</p>
                     <p>Every other Warrant, called double Warrants,<note place="margin">viii. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a <hi>poſt Termin.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The Lord Maior of London his War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant,<note place="margin">v. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="37" facs="tcp:66379:22"/>The Secondaries of the Compters in Eaſter Terme yearely,<note place="margin">13. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of an Attournies name in the Roll of Attournies, upon his firſt admittance,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Warrant upon a Writ of Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant, <hi>per ordin. Cur.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>William Rolfe.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <p>Paid to the Clarke by every Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney iiii. d. a Terme, called the Roll groat, which is paid to the Judges Box, and I conceive it to be due ever ſince 11. <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Paid alſo to the Clarke by the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thonotaries xii. d. upon every Recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, which is alſo paid to the Judges,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>To the Clarke when an Attourney is firſt ſworne,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Chirographers</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> The ancient Fee limitted by Stat. 11. <hi>Eliz.</hi> for every Fine,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> From 4. <hi>H.</hi> 7. for the ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice in proclaiming Fines,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> By Stat. 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi> for writing the Roll,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>So the Chirographers Fee for every Fine is,<note place="margin">v. s.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="38" facs="tcp:66379:23"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Other Fees alſo due, and anci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently paid to the <hi>Chirographer, videlicet,</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr exemplifying a Fine the Term in which it was ingroſſed,<note place="margin">ii. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete of every Fine, of twelve lines copied out of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſight of every Record being ancient, from H. 8. upwards,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſearch of every Fine from H. 8. to this preſent, for every yeare,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſearch of every Fine during the raigne of H. 8. for every yeare,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For certifying of every Record by a Writ of Error,<note place="margin">xii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Quid juris clamat, quae reddat, reddit, &amp; per quae ſervic.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">vi. s. v. s</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring a claime upon a Record,</p>
                     <p>For allowing of Proclamations upon Fines brought into the Office after the Terme ended,<note place="margin">vi. d. xiiii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the <hi>poſt Termin<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi> of a Fine,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>William Blake.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="39" facs="tcp:66379:23"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>The <hi>Chirographers Clarkes</hi> Fees for ingroſſing of Fines by the Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies which ſue them out.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>THe Chirographers Clarks have received an allowance of the Attournies for their paines for them, which heretofore have been more advantagious unto them than now it is, being reduced to ii. s. vi. d. in cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine, had and made at the requeſt of 100. or 80. of the moſt ancient At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tournies, with <hi>Iohn Brewer</hi> Eſquire, Clarke of the ſaid Office, in 2. or 3. of King <hi>Iames:</hi> To which agreement had and made in writing, the ſaid At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tournies ſet to their hands, and the ſame was delivered to Sir <hi>Edw: Cooke</hi> Knight, then chiefe Juſtice of the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas, and hath ſo continued ever ſince,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For this allowance the Clarkes doe write more than all the Officers through which Fines doe paſte, <hi>viz.</hi> They write every Fine long or ſhort, foure times over in a great ſet hand.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Randall.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="40" facs="tcp:66379:24"/>
                     <head>Fees belonging to the Clarke of the <hi>Treaſurie.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>FOr the copie of every iſſue, and impur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ance for every ſheete,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Judgement, Deed en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled, and reall Action, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſearch of every Terme above ten yeares,<note place="margin">iv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Exemplification not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">vii. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <p>For every Record of <hi>Niſi prius</hi> not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheete more,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Ex. per Duncombe Cler. Theſaurar. <hi>Tho: Richardſon,</hi> mil.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>Fees for the Keeper of the <hi>Treaſurie</hi> from <hi>11. Eliz.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For ſearch of a Terme a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove ten yeares,<note place="margin">viii. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſeven yeares under ten years,</p>
                     <p>For three yeares,</p>
                     <p>For ſearch of a Plea Roll,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="41" facs="tcp:66379:24"/>For a Roll carried into the Court,<note place="margin">vi. d. iii. s. xii. d. v. s. ii. s. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For making up a Term and Record,</p>
                     <p>For every Attourney ſworn in Court,</p>
                     <p>For a Jurie at Bar,</p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Niſi prius</hi> in Midd.</p>
                     <p>For a Wager in Law,</p>
                     <p>For a copie of a <hi>Precipe</hi> after the Terme,<note place="margin">xviii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Fine acknowledged in the Treaſurie,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Warrant of Attourney loſt, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>entred, and comes to be entred in the Roll after the Terme,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For an entrie loſt out of the Kings ſilver, and comes to be entred in the Office,<note place="margin">iv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>From the Clarke of the Treaſurie for my attendance every Terme,<note place="margin">v. s. xviiid.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For my Key after the Terme,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>William Weſe.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="42" facs="tcp:66379:25"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Theſe be the Fees which I <hi>Henry Ewer,</hi> Clarke of the Kings ſilver have taken ſince I became Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer, which was <hi>in Mich. 16. Iac. Reg.</hi> and were uſually taken be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that time by Maſter <hi>Gulſon</hi> my Predeceſſor in the ſaid Office, and I doe believe they were due <hi>in Anno 11 Eliz.</hi> except iiii. d. encreaſed by order of Court <hi>in Hillar. An. 8. Iac. Reg.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For the Fees of every or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary Fine taken by the Lord chiefe Juſtice of the common Pleas, or any Judge of Aſſize in the Weſtern Circuit, together with the copie, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>poſt fine,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xviii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Fine taken in the ſame Circuit by ſpeciall Commiſſion, and for the copie of the <hi>poſt fine,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xxii d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ordinary Fine elſewhere in England, and Munmouthſhire taken as aforeſaid without Commiſſion, and for the copie,<note place="margin">x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Fine taken by ſpeciall Commiſſion out of the Weſterne Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuit, and for the copie,<note place="margin">xiv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſeveral Caption in any Fine
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:66379:25"/>
where it is taken at ſeverall times by ſpeciall Commiſſion, over and above the former rates,<note place="margin">iiii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Fine certified by <hi>certiorari</hi> after the death of any Judge, or other Commiſſioners, over and above the former rates,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the <hi>poſt Termin<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi> of every Fine brought in the next Vacation after the retourne of the Writ of Covenant,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſearch of any Fine every Terme,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every copie of the Entrie of the Kings ſilver,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Fee of a <hi>Ne recipiatur</hi> of any Fine either by Order or Warrant of the Court, or any Judge,<note place="margin">iii. s4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the continuing of any ſuch Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der or Warrant from Te me to Terme till it be diſſolved,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Hen: Ewer.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Phillizers</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For every Cap. al. &amp; plur. Cap. in Debt, Detinue, and Treſpaſſe, not having more than foure names in a Writ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>, and Entrie thereof,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For delivery of every firſt Cap.
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:66379:26"/>
upon Record, and Entrie thereof,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Teſtat.</hi> upon any of the ſaid Writs, <hi>pon. in Replevin &amp; Summons,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Cap. al. &amp; plur. in Accompt, Covenant, Annuity, <hi>Ejectio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ne firme,</hi> and upon penall Stat.<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Writ in an action upon the Caſe, or more, according to the length,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every retourn. <hi>habend.</hi> and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond deliverance before appearance and entrie thereof,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Non omit. &amp; cap.</hi> in Wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thernam,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ of partition, <hi>warrant. charte, Quare imp.</hi> and Waſte,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ for enquiry of da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages in reall actions, <hi>Scire ſac. &amp; Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſid.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every graund <hi>cap. al. ſum. pet. cap.</hi> and entrie thereof,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copy of the entrie thereof,</p>
                     <p>For the demaundant in every Writ of View, and entrie thereof,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copie of the entrie thereof,</p>
                     <p>For every Writ of ſeizin and entrie thereof,<note place="margin">iv. s. vi. d ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the view paper,</p>
                     <p>For a copie of the entrie thereof,</p>
                     <p>For every Writ of <hi>Habeas corpus, duc. coram diſtring. imp. vic. &amp; diſtring. ball.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ of reſcous and entry thereof,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="45" facs="tcp:66379:26"/>For the entrie of every adjournment, diſcontinuance, and reſort,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſpeciall baile, and the en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trie thereof,<note place="margin">iis. x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every comparence in reall and mixt actions,<note place="margin">iv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every comparence upon Writs to arreſt, and the entrie thereof,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Searches, Copies, Number Rols, and giving of rules, each of them,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>
                        <hi>Exigenters</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>EVer ſince the Stat. of <hi>H.</hi> 8. which gave the Proclamation upon the Exigent, the whole eſtate of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>igenters Office did conſiſt in the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of three Writs, <hi>videlicet,</hi> an Exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent, a Superſid, and a Proclamation, All which Writs are warranted by one and the ſame Record.</p>
                     <p>For all the time of our remembrance and experience in the ſaid Court, which hath been (by the moſt ancient of us) for about thirty yeares, or therea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout, the Fees of the ſaid Writs were as followeth, <hi>videlicet;</hi>
                     </p>
                     <list>
                        <item>The Superſid.<note place="margin">ii. s. xi. d. vi. d.</note>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Exigent,</item>
                        <item>The Proclamation,</item>
                     </list>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="46" facs="tcp:66379:27"/>Which Fee of vi. d. was given by the Stat. of 6. <hi>H.</hi> 8. being now about one hundred and ten yeares ſince.</p>
                     <p>About eight or nine yeares ſince the Superſid. (<hi>quia improvide</hi>) being the leaſt Writ in labour, and more in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit than both the other, was granted by Letters Patents under the great Seale of England, by the late King of fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous memory, to Maſter <hi>Iohn Murray,</hi> then of his Majeſties Bedchamber, and partly to avoid conteſtation with his ſaid Majeſties graunt, and upon hopes and promiſes of ſome recompence ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther way, the Exigenters did give way to the ſaid Patent, and have ever ſince loſt the benefit of the ſaid Superſid. whereupon the Judges did give en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe only of i. d. to be taken upon the Exigent, for relieſe of the Exigenters and their Clarkes, and ſo the Exigent was made xii. d. which increaſe of i. d. is all the recompence which hitherto they have received for that great loſſe of the Superſid.</p>
                     <p>We have likewiſe heard that about forty yeares ſince, and before our times by occaſion of an Act of Parliament, made 31. <hi>Eliz.</hi> whereby the Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Exigent was much enlarged without any addition or encreaſe of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ee, there was i. d. added to the Exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent to be given to the poore Clarkes
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:66379:27"/>
for writing the ſaid Writs over and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the ancient allowance, which i. d. hath ever ſince been paid to the ſaid poore Clarkes accordingly, without any benefit to the Maſters themſelves.</p>
                     <p>Other increaſe, addition, or alterati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Fees in our Offices we know not of, nor ever heard of, although the length of the ſaid Exigent, or Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation with their entries, conſidering the length of the Superſid. (All which we humbly ſubmit to his Majeſties Commiſſioners) might perhaps have juſtly deſerved ſome further improve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. And it is certainly true, that no other encreaſe of Fees hath been in our Offices ſince 11. <hi>Eliz.</hi> nor for ought we ever heard, or can by any meanes conjecture for theſe hundred yeares at the leaſt.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>
                           <list>
                              <item>Rich: Page.</item>
                              <item>Charles Cooke.</item>
                              <item>Dan: Holford.</item>
                              <item>Io: Millington.</item>
                           </list>
                        </signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="part">
                  <pb n="48" facs="tcp:66379:28"/>
                  <opener>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>
                           <hi>HILLAR. TERTIO</hi> Caroli Regis.</date>
                     </dateline>
                  </opener>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Clarke of the <hi>Jurors.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>A note of all ſuch Fees as are now uſually taken by the Clarkes of the <hi>Iurors</hi> of his Maieſties Court of Common Pleas at Weſtm. be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſame, and no other then ſuch as have been taken time out of minde.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For a Writ of <hi>hab. corp. Jurator.</hi> in debt and treſpaſſe,<note place="margin">x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the like Writ in all other actions,<note place="margin">xvi. d. ii. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Diſtring. <hi>cum decem Tales,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Termes ſearch, the copie of a Jurie, a number Roll, and a diſcontinu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance and adjourum: for every of them,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Io: Adie.<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                        </signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="49" facs="tcp:66379:28"/>
                     <head>The Clarke of the <hi>Eſſoines.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For every Eſſoine and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ception,<note place="margin">iiii. d. iiii. d. iv. d. ii. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every adjournment,</p>
                     <p>For the copie,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Idem dies,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Nonſuit for want of ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>journment in actions perſonall,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d xii. d. 4. s. iv. d xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Copie,</p>
                     <p>For every Nonſuit in Actions reall,</p>
                     <p>For the copie,</p>
                     <p>For the exemplification of every Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoine and Nonſuit thereupon when it ſhall happen, being very ſeldome,<note place="margin">7. s. vi. d 3. s. iv. d xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copie thereof,</p>
                     <p>For the Clarke,</p>
                     <p>For ſeverall Fees from ſeverall Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of the Court towards the numbring and marking of the Rolls,<note place="margin">4. l. 9. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Fran: Hurſt.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="50" facs="tcp:66379:29"/>
                     <head>
                        <hi>Outlawrie</hi> Office.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>In the Kings Attourney generall his Office of the Outlaries exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted by his Deputy Maſter <hi>Iohnſon,</hi> the Fees are as follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, <hi>viz.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr a ſpeciall Cap. <hi>Vtlagat.</hi> againſt body, lands, and goods,<note place="margin">ii. s. 4. d. xiiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a propr.</p>
                     <p>For every Writ of <hi>hab. corp. &amp; du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces tecum,</hi> when they are ſued forth,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d xiiii. d. x. d. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If a propr.</p>
                     <p>For a generall Cap. <hi>Vtlagat.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>If a propr.</p>
                     <p>For ingroſſing and certifying a ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciall VVrit, with the Inquiſition re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourned by the Sheriffe, of lands, or goods found thereupon, and for the Exigent, with the retourne thereof at large certified into the Exchequer, when it is required, the Office Fee is viii. s. unleſſe it be commanded by the Lord Treaſurer, Chancellor, or Barons
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:66379:29"/>
of the Exchequer, or by the Kings At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourney generall, or Sollicitor, for his Majeſties ſervice only, then no Fee is<note place="margin">
                           <hi>viii. s.</hi> aut nil.</note> due.</p>
                     <p>For ingroſſing and certifying a re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſall into the Exchequer to diſcharge Seizures upon Outlaries, when any is,<note place="margin">v. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And to the Clarke,</p>
                     <p>For entring the reverſall in the Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larie Office to diſcharge all Proceſſe thereupon, or upon any Writ of Error,<note place="margin">ii. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For certifying of an Outlarie, or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſall when it is pleaded,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And to the Clarke,</p>
                     <p>For ſearch of an Outlarie one Term (as in all other Offices) iiii. d. if above a yeare, then iii. d. a Terme, which is<note place="margin">iiii. d. iii. d.</note> the utmoſt,</p>
                     <p>For entring and filing of an Exigent, with one proceſſe thereupon,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Theſe ſeverall Fees aforeſaid were paid and received in Eaſter Terme 34. <hi>Eliz.</hi> and ever ſince to mine own knowledge, for ſo long I have been and continued Clark and Deputy to all Attournies ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerall that have been ſince that time.</p>
                     <p>Theſe (as I underſtand) are the true Fees.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Ro. Heath.<lb/>
Will. Iohnſon.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="52" facs="tcp:66379:30"/>
                     <head>The Fees of the Seale for Writs.</head>
                     <p>ALL VVrits of the Kings Bench and Common Pleas,<note place="margin">vii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>The exemplifications of the Kings Bench,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>The exemplifications of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas,<note place="margin">ii. s. ii. d. i. d. i. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Outlaries,</p>
                     <p>Propr.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Ri: Ligon.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>Fees due to the Marſhall and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamator of the Court of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas given by Order made by all the Iudges of the Court, <hi>Term. Trin. 31. H. 1. poſt Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſtum,</hi> and received according<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly by the ſaid Marſhall and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamator, for any thing appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth to the contrary, untill <hi>11. Eliz.</hi> and ever ſince.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For every Judgement, and Nonſuit,<note place="margin">iiii. d. viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every Fine,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="53" facs="tcp:66379:30"/>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> For every finall judgement,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>William Senkey,</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <p>Chiefe Uſher of the Exchequer, and Marſhall, and Proclamator of the ſaid Court of common Pleas by Leaſe from <hi>Clement Walker</hi> Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire, who hath the ſame Office in inheritance by graund Serje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>antie.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The foure <hi>Cryers.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>HEreafter doe enſue the good Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinances and Rules made aſwell by the Kings Juſtices of the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas in times paſt, as by the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices now being for the good rule and order of the ſaid Court, which ſame now Juſtices doe charge and command every of the ſaid Officers and Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies well and truly to obſerve and keep upon the paines therein limited.</p>
                     <p>Which ſaid orders were enrolled <hi>Termin. Trin. 35. H. 1. poſt conqueſtum rot. 494. Io: Prieſt</hi> chiefe Juſtice of the common Pleas, <hi>Ni. Auſten, Pet. Arder, Ro. Davers, Ro. Dawbie, Wa. Moile,</hi> and <hi>Iohn Needeham,</hi> Juſt. of the ſame Court.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="54" facs="tcp:66379:31"/>
                     <head>The Cryers Fees from <hi>11. Eliz.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>FOr every judgement,<note place="margin">iiii. d. xii. d. iiii. d. viii. d. viii. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every finall judgement,</p>
                     <p>For every Nonſuit,</p>
                     <p>For every Fine,</p>
                     <p>For every Recovery,</p>
                     <p>For calling a Jury if they fill not,</p>
                     <p>For every Jurie if they fill, and ſerve, and give up their Verdict the ſame day, at the Bar the ſame day, and for keeping them till then,<note place="margin">xvi. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If the Jurie lie all night, that we be forced to watch and waite on them all night,<note place="margin">xxx. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For carrying every bundle of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords out of the Treaſurie into the Court, and back again into the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurie,<note place="margin">vi. d. vi. s. xii. d. xii. d. 4. s. 4. d. iv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Attourney that is ſworne,</p>
                     <p>For every Baile,</p>
                     <p>For every Oath in Court,</p>
                     <p>For every wager of Law old Fees,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Scire fac.</hi> called in Court,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Niſi prius</hi> before my Lord chiefe Juſtice,<note place="margin">iv. s. xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Guardian,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Ro. Heliard,<lb/>
Iohn Philpot,<lb/>
Tho: wickman,<lb/>
William Weſt.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="55" facs="tcp:66379:31"/>
                     <head>The Fees of the keeper of the Court, from <hi>11. Eliz.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>FRom the Clarke of the Treaſurie for hanging the cloath of the Court,<note place="margin">vi. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a wager of Law, and Wager<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men,<note place="margin">ix. s. 6. d v. s. xii. d. ii. s. iv. d. iiii. d. iiii. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Jurie at Bar,</p>
                     <p>For every Attourney ſworn in Court,</p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Niſi prius</hi> in Midd.</p>
                     <p>For a Baile,</p>
                     <p>For a Fine,</p>
                     <p>For a Deed acknowledged,</p>
                     <p>For ſatisfaction acknowledged,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Will: Weſe.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>The Fees of the Clarke of the <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rollments</hi> of Fines and Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veries.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> The Fee due to the Judges by the Stat. of 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi> for inrol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of every Fine and Recovery,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Item,</hi> Due to the Judges by the ſame Stat. for exemplifying every inrol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,<note place="margin">v. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="56" facs="tcp:66379:32"/>For ſearch of every Fine inrolled for every yeare,<note place="margin">xvi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For copying every Fine inrolled, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Clarkes Fee for inrolling by the Roll,<note place="margin">8. s. 8. d. 8. s. 4. d. 3. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For exemplifying after the ſame rate,</p>
                     <p>For every rule upon amendments,</p>
                     <p>For retourning VVrits of Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants upon Fines, and VVrits of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries, Summons, and Seizins upon common Recoveries, as deputy of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord for Sheriffes appointed by the Court, the ancient Fee is,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Porter</hi> of the Court, his Fees from <hi>11. Eliz.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>FOr every VVrit of Entrie with M. Attourney generall,<note place="margin">iiii. d. v. s. ii. s. vi. d. iiii. d. iiii. d. ii. d. xii. d. iv. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Jury at Bar,</p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Niſi prius,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a wager of Law,</p>
                     <p>For a Fine acknowledged,</p>
                     <p>For a Baile,</p>
                     <p>For ſatisfaction acknowledged,</p>
                     <p>For the Attournies Oath,</p>
                     <p>For a Guardian,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Jo: Wade.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="57" facs="tcp:66379:32"/>
                     <head>
                        <hi>Alienation</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THo: Ravenſcroft, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rat Poulton, Geo: Coultrop, Eſquires Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners.</p>
                     <p>Tho: Bond Eſquire, Receiver.</p>
                     <p>Take no Fees, but receive a certaine ſtipend from the King.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>Fees taken by the Maſter of the <hi>Chancery,</hi> for that Office ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr ſignifying every Docquet up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Licence and Pardon of Alie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ of Entrie, for lands holden in chiefe,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Writs of Entrie of lands not holden in chiefe,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="58" facs="tcp:66379:33"/>For Affidavits upon diſcharge of<note place="margin">ii. s.</note> Tenures,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Anth: Croſts.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>The uſuall Fees taken in the Office of <hi>Compoſitions,</hi> for alienations, by the Clarkes there.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr a certificate upon a Writ of Entrie,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the warrant to the great Seale for pardon of Alienation,<note place="margin">x. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For viewing the Subjects evidences, ſearch of the Tenures, and drawing of the Affidavit with Proces, to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged,<note place="margin">vi. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a releaſe in nature of a Pardon of alienation upon a common Recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, and for the like releaſe upon a ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciall Livery, and alſo for a releaſe up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a generall pardon at the Coronati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or other times for each of them,<note place="margin">13. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the note of a Sheriffes diſcharge upon a ſeizure,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Ex. and for certifying thereof into the Exchequer,<note place="margin">xii. d. vi. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Sheriffes acquittance,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Hum: Hurleſton.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="59" facs="tcp:66379:33"/>
                     <p>FOr entring in a large booke every Writ of Covenant fineable, <hi>videli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cet,</hi> in the Terme time,<note place="margin">vi. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And in the Vacation,</p>
                     <p>For entring in another book remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the ſaid Office every Docquer upon a licence of Alienation in the Terme time,<note place="margin">xii. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And in the Vacation,</p>
                     <p>For every Docquet for a pardon of Alienation in proces of <hi>Diſtring<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi> or <hi>Scire fac.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ of entrie of Lands holden <hi>in capite,</hi> and entred in the ſame booke,<note place="margin">vi. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And in the Vacation,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Hen: Smith.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <p>FOr endorſing every writ of Entry,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For endorſing every writ of Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant in Terme,<note place="margin">iiii. d. vi. d. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>In the Vacation,</p>
                     <p>For entring unfiled VVrits,</p>
                     <p>For drawing the diſcharges of Tenures in Parliament, and entring them,<note place="margin">vii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Hugh Dodd.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="60" facs="tcp:66379:34"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>The Vnderſheriffe of Middleſex taketh theſe Fees following in his Maieſties Court of Common Pleas.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr a Warrant upon a Cap. for every name,<note place="margin">iiii. d. ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For retourne of a <hi>Venire fac.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Warrant upon a Cap. <hi>Vtlagat.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For retourne of a <hi>Hab. corpora Iura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torum,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſummoning the jurie, for every name,<note place="margin">iiii. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Cepi corpus</hi> for every man,</p>
                     <p>For retourne of an Exigent for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry man,<note place="margin">iiii. d. xii. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For retourne of a Proclamation,</p>
                     <p>For retourne of a <hi>Scire fac.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For retourne of a <hi>Nihil overat. &amp; Fier. fac.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Iames Prym Subvic.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="61" facs="tcp:66379:34"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleete,</hi> his Fees.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>A note of the Fees due and belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Warden of the Fleete, and under-Officers, as appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth by a Commiſſion under the great Seale of England from the late Queene <hi>Eliz.</hi> in the third yeare of the raigne, and confirm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the 37. yeare of her raigne, what every ſeverall priſoner in their ſeverall degrees ought to pay.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>AN Archbiſhop, A Duke, A Dur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſſe, Are to pay for their Commitment Fee to the ſaid Warden and his Officers, having the<note place="margin">I. s. 21. 10.</note> firſt weekes dyet with wine,</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry<note place="margin">I. s. d. 3. 6. 8.</note> weekly dyet with wine,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="62" facs="tcp:66379:35"/>A Marquis, A Marqueſſes, An Earle, A Counteſſe, A Vice-Counteſſe, Are to pay for their Commitment Fee to the ſaid Warden and his Officers,<note place="margin">I. s. 14. 11.</note> having the firſt weekes dyet,</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary weekly dyet with wine,<note place="margin">2. I.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>A Lord Spirituall, or Temporall, A Lady, the wife of a Baron, or Lord, Are to pay for their Commitment Fee as aboveſaid, having the firſt weekes<note place="margin">I. s. d 11. 5. 10</note> dyet with wine,</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry<note place="margin">I. s. d. 1. 6. 8.</note> weekly commons with wine,</p>
                     <p>A Knight, A Lady, the wife of a Knight, A Doctor of Divinity, A Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor of Law, or others of like calling; Are to pay as aforeſaid for their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitment Fee, having the firſt weekes<note place="margin">I. s. 5. 1.</note> dyet with wine,</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry<note place="margin">s. d. 18. 6.</note> weekly commons with wine,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="63" facs="tcp:66379:35"/>An Eſquire, A Gentleman, A Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlewoman that ſhall ſit at the Parlour commons, or any perſon under that de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree, that ſhall be at the ſame com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons; Are to pay for their Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Fee as aforeſaid, having the firſt<note place="margin">I. s. d. 3. 6. 8.</note> weekes dyet with wine,</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry weekly commons with wine,<note place="margin">10. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>A Yeoman, or any others that ſhall be at the Hall commons, man or wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man; Are to pay for their Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Fee, having the firſt weekes dyet.</p>
                     <p>Alſo they are to pay for their ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry weekly Commons,<note place="margin">5. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>A poore man in the Ward, that hath part of the Boxe; Is to pay for his Commitment Fee, having no dyet,<note place="margin">7. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="64" facs="tcp:66379:36"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Alſo there is due to the ſaid War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den xx. d. <hi>per diem,</hi> for the whole day, and x. d. for the halfe day, for every man that he may lawfully licenſe to go abroad.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>MOreover the ſaid Warden hath retourne of Writs as Sheriffes, and Bailiſſes of liberties have, by which he hath allowance for retourn of every <hi>Hab. corp.</hi> or Attachment,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Alſo for every <hi>Habeas corpus cum cauſa,</hi> there are Fees for retourning the cauſes, <hi>videlicet:</hi>
                     </p>
                     <list>
                        <item>For allowing the Writ,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d ii. s.</note>
                        </item>
                        <item>For retourning the firſt cauſe,</item>
                        <item>For every execution,</item>
                        <item>For every action,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                     <p>Which are due to the Wardens Clarkes, and v. s. to the Wardens ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants for bringing every priſoner ſafe to the Bar.</p>
                     <p>Alſo he hath for allowance of every Superſid. and diſcharge,<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="65" facs="tcp:66379:36"/>Alſo when any man is committed by Order out of the Courts of Starch am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, Chancery, Court of Wards and Liveries, Court of Exchequer, Court of Requeſts, and Court of Duchie, the VVardens ſervants (being ſent to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend them, and bring them to the Fleete, according to the tenour of their commitment) have iiii. d. the mile where they are apprehended, and iv. d. the mile backe againe, and the Clarke hath ii. s. for making the Writ.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Hen: Lell<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="part">
                  <pb n="66" facs="tcp:66379:37"/>
                  <head>
                     <hi>THE JVRORS PRE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentment,</hi> Februarii, 15. 1627.</head>
                  <div type="certificate">
                     <p>THE Certificate of us whoſe names are here under-writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, Attournies of the Court of Common Pleas, given and preſented the fifteenth day of Febr. 1627. unto his Majeſties Commiſſioners for inquirie after exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted Fees, and innovated Offices ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Oath to us, by them in that behalfe adminiſtred.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Inprimis,</hi> As concerning what Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces were uſually holden, kept, or exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted in the ſaid Court, in the eleventh yeare of the raigne of our late Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raigne Lady Queene <hi>Elizabeth;</hi> Wee ſay that our knowledges doe not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend ſo far, but for the time of our re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective knowledges, there hath beene
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:66379:37"/>
in the ſaid Court, theſe particular Of<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fices and Places following, <hi>videlicet:</hi>
                     </p>
                     <list>
                        <item>The <hi>Cuſtos Brevium.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Prothonotaries.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Warrants.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Chirographer.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Treaſury.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Outlaries.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Proclamator</hi> of the <hi>Court.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Cryers</hi> of the Court, whom we take to be but Subſtitutes to the Proclamator.</item>
                        <item>The <hi>Clarke</hi> of the Kings ſilver.</item>
                        <item>The <hi>Phillizers.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Exigenters.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Iuries.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Errors.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The <hi>Seale</hi> Office.</item>
                        <item>The Clarke of the <hi>Eſſoines.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Keeper of the <hi>Court.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>The Office of <hi>Inrollments,</hi> of <hi>Fines</hi> and <hi>Recoveries,</hi> erected by Sta.</item>
                        <item>The <hi>Porter</hi> of the Court.</item>
                     </list>
                     <p>And for new e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ected Offices, we ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver knew of any other, then the Office following.</p>
                     <p>An Office called the <hi>Superſideas</hi> Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, which (as we are informed) is
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:66379:38"/>
granted by Letters Patents under the great Scale of England.</p>
                     <p>Touching what Fees, Rewards, Summe, or Summes of money were in the ſaid eleventh yeare of the raigne of our ſaid late Soveraigne Queene <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zabeth,</hi> or at any time ſince uſually, or accuſtomably taken, received, or had by the Judges, Counſellours, or Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctilers, Officers, or their deputies, or other Miniſters, Clarkes, Regiſters, or Attournies of the ſaid Court, we doe certifie as followeth, <hi>videlicet:</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>The <hi>Iudges</hi> Fees that have beene uſually, or accuſtomably paid, during our remembrances, <hi>viz.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> For allowing a Writ of Error upon a ſingle judgement,<note place="margin">17. s. 6. d</note> For allowance of a Writ of Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ror upon a judgement, upon a <hi>Scire fac.</hi> or upon an Outlarie after judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,<note place="margin">3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſigning every Writ of privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge <hi>Procedendo Superſid.</hi> upon a <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cedend.</hi> or <hi>Hab. corp.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Baile upon a Writ of privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge at then Chamber, one cauſe on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly being certified,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every cauſe more,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="69" facs="tcp:66379:38"/>For a Prohibition,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For confeſſing a judgement at a Judges Chamber,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For an Affidavit before a Judge out of Court,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging of a Fine out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For certifying of a Fine, or retourne of a <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem,</hi> and not of the <hi>Precipe,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xvi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Warrant of Attourney for Recovery taken out of the Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For reverſing of an Outlarie out of Court for one name,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every other name,</p>
                     <p>For every witneſſe for the proofe of a ſuggeſtion upon a Prohibition out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For admiſſion of a Guardian out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d. 9. s. 8. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a privie Verdict,</p>
                     <p>For ſigning of an Information,</p>
                     <p>For a licence to compound upon an Information,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging of a deed to bee inrolled in Court,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging of a deed out of Court to be inrolled ix. s. viii. d. now they take but<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For taking of a ſpeciall Baile upon meane proces out of Court, in the Phil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lizers<note place="margin">xii. d</note> office in Terme,</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="70" facs="tcp:66379:39"/>For taking a ſpeciall Baile upon meane proces after the Terme,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Warrant under a Judges hand to paſſe a Fine, where are more than three Cognizois, or three Cog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizees, which was not taken till 12. <hi>Iac. Reg. per ord. cur.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>Serjeants Fees.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>As for Counſellors, there are none attending at the Court of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas, other then Serieants at Law, whoſe ancient Fees have been as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr a motion, or ſetting his hand to a ſpeciall Plea,<note place="margin">x. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a triall at Barre, or an argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment upon a demurrer,<note place="margin">xx. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing a Recovery at Bar to every Serjeant uſed in the ſame Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For declaring of a Fine at Bar,</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="71" facs="tcp:66379:39"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Cuſtos Brevium.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Fees mentioned in the Certificate under Maſter <hi>Spen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers</hi> hand hereto annexed are the uſuall, and accuſtomed Fees, which during our remembrance have been paid, Except.</p>
                     <p>The ſumme of xii. d. demanded in the Fees of every Fine formerly certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, which of late times hath been taken more than heretofore was anciently ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken, and was firſt claimed by them for retourne of Writs of Covenant under colour of Deputations from the She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffes, and now is claimed for keeping three parts of a Fine which we hold not to be due.</p>
                     <p>Alſo the xx. d. demanded for filing of every Writ after the Terme, and ſo for every Terme after xx. d. whereas the Fee of xx. d. is not to be paid for filing of any Writ after any Terme, unleſſe it be filed after the laſt filing day of the next ſubſequent Terme, after the retourne thereof, and more then xx. d. ought not to be paid for filing of any Writ, unleſſe it be above a yeare after the retourne.</p>
                     <p>Alſo the Fee of xii. d. for filing of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:66379:40"/>
Writ of Entrie, Summons, and Sci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zin upon common Recoveries taken by the Clarkes of that Office, which wee hold not to be due, for that iiii. d. ought to be paid and taken as their Maſters Fee for a <hi>poſt diem.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>And we alſo certifie that there hath been uſually and accuſtomably paid to the <hi>Cuſtos Brevium,</hi> or his Clarkes the Fees following, <hi>videlicet.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Ne reciptatur,</hi> comming under a Judges hand, or by order in Court,<note place="margin">xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every note of Jurors names for the Clarke of the Juries to make fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther proces by,<note place="margin">viii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every note of an Exigent, for the Clarke of the Outlaries to make fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther proces by,<note place="margin">viii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copying of every Writ, or other Record, for every Sheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>h of any booke of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries of any Writs, for every Terme ſearching,<note place="margin">iiii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>As for the reſt of the Fees mentioned in the ſaid Certificate, the ſame being Fees demanded by the Clarkes of the <hi>Cuſtos Brevium</hi> his Office, and Bag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bearer to be allowed them by the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter of the ſaid Office, we know not any ſuch Fees to be due unto them, and doe certifie, that if any ſuch be, the ſame are to be paid to the ſame
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:66379:40"/>
Clarkes, and Bag-bearer by their ſaid Maſter out of the Fees before recited, and no others.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>FIrſt, we doe finde nothing to the contrary, but that all the Fees cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified by the ſaid Prothonotaries, are the uſuall Fees that have been accuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mably paid during the time of our re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membrance, but we certifie further that there hath been taken by the ſpace often yeares laſt paſt, or there abouts upon every judgement in perſonall, and mixt actions over and above the ii. s. in the Bill of their Fee, certified, and more than anciently was paid, xii. d: which they informe us the judges have for aſſeſſing of Coſts.</p>
                     <p>There hath been alſo taken by their Clarkes for about twelve or fourteene yeares laſt paſt iiii. s. for the reverſall of every Outlarie in Court not former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly taken, neither is it certified by them which wee are informed is for the Iudges Fee in liew of an m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>nt Fee of ix. s. viii. d. due to the Iudges, when the ſame wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="5 letters">
                           <desc>•••••</desc>
                        </gap>ſed at their Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="74" facs="tcp:66379:41"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Secondaries</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>THere hath been taken by them by the ſpace of ſixteene yeares laſt paſt, or thereabouts xii. d. upon every common Recovery drawne at the Bar, more than formerly, or is now certified by the Prothonotaries, but the reaſon, or ground thereof we know not.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Clarke</hi> of the <hi>Warrants</hi> Of<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fice.</head>
                     <p>VVEE can ſay nothing againſt the Certificate of the Fees of the Clarkes of this Office, but that they have uſually been accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed to be paid during our remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance, ſaving.</p>
                     <p>That there is, and hath been by the ſpace of eleven yeares or thereabouts taken by him more than formerly up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on every Fine iiii. d. for a Warrant of Attourney which we know not to bee uſed before.</p>
                     <p>Alſo there is in the laſt mentioned Certificate certified only by Maſter
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:66379:41"/>
                        <hi>Mene</hi> mentioned to be paid to the Clarks of the ſaid Prothonotaries xii. d. upon every Recovery, which we know not to be due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Phillizers</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>VVEE doe alſo certifie that the Fees mentioned in the Certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficate of the Phillizers, inti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuled, the Fees which the Phillizers of the common Pleas now take, have been uſually and accuſtomably paid during our remembrance for ought we know to the contrary, ſaving,</p>
                     <p>That there is taken iiii. d. upon eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry firſt Cap. and viii. d. upon every ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance of the Defendant in every action more than was formerly taken before 14. <hi>Iac. Reg.</hi> which is ſo taken by vertue of an order of the Judges made upon the reaſons expreſſed in the ſaid Order.</p>
                     <p>And for the viii. d. claimed for the copie of the entrie of every grand Cap. al. Summons &amp; Pet. Cap. wee know it not to be due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="76" facs="tcp:66379:42"/>
                     <head>In the Exigenters Office.</head>
                     <p>VVEE alſo certifie that the Fee of ii. s. for a <hi>Superſid.</hi> for ſuch of them as were made in the ſaid Office, was anciently, and uſually taken in the ſaid Office, until a Patent was granted of the ſaid <hi>uperſid.</hi> and that the Fee of x. d. was anciently and uſually taken untill about 31. <hi>Eliz.</hi> for every Exigent except propr. and that ever ſince there hath been taken more for every Exigent i. d. and for the ſpace of ſixe yeares laſt paſt, or there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts, i. d. more; The reaſons wee know not, but refer the ſame unto the certificate of the Exigemers.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Chirographers</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>VVEE acknowledge that the Fees certified by the Chiro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grapher himſelfe, are the u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid all the time of our reſpective knowledges, but as to the Fees certifi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed under Maſter <hi>Randals</hi> hand for the Clarkes Fees of that Office, we know
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:66379:42"/>
no ſuch Fees due to them for writing the Chirograph of the ſaid Fine, but we ſay, there hath been uſed to bee given to the ſaid Clarke that in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groſleth the ſaid Fine xii. d. for a gratuity.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of the Kings ſilver.</head>
                     <p>VVEE certifie that the ancient and uſuall Fees for entring the Kings ſilver, of every Fine was only vi. d. and for every <hi>Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiorari</hi> for every Fine certified by <hi>Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiorari</hi> after the death of a Judge vi. d. and for every ſearch for a Fine for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Terme iiii. d. and for the copie of the entrie of the Silver, for every ſheet viii. d. if the copie be required, and for every <hi>Ne reciptatur,</hi> or <hi>Ne intratur</hi> of a Fine xii. d. And if the Fine come in after a Terme, and after the Rolls are made up to be delivered up out of their hands, the ſaid Clarke of the Kings ſil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver was allowed reaſonable recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence for his paines, but no certaine Fee.</p>
                     <p>And as concerning all the other Fees mentioned in the Certificate un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the hand of Maſter <hi>Henry Fwer</hi> Clarke of the Kings ſilver, We certifie
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:66379:43"/>
that the ſame were taken by the ſaid Clarke of late yeares, and ſince the ſaid eleventh yeare of the ſaid late Queene <hi>Eliz.</hi> the moſt ancient of them being not above thirty yeares or there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts, and the reſt of far later time, whereof iiii. d. he demandeth by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of an Order of the Iudges in that behalfe made: The copie whereof, is to the Certificate annexed.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of the <hi>Clarke</hi> of the <hi>Treaſurie.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Fees mentioned in the Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate under the hand of the Lord chiefe Iuſtice <hi>Richardſon,</hi> for the Fees of the Clarke of the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſury, we acknowledge to be the uſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid during our remembrance, Except, <hi>videlicet:</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>viii. d. of the iiii. s. demanded for ſearch of every Terme above ten years the ancient Fee due to the Clarke of the Treaſurie is but iii. s. iiii. d. and the viii. d. reſidue is due to the keeper of the Treaſurie, and is claimed by him in his Certificate.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="79" facs="tcp:66379:43"/>And we alſo certifie that beſides the Fees certified by the Lord chiefe Iuſtice <hi>Richardſon,</hi> there is due to the under Clarke in the Treaſurie for examining any booke or old Record of <hi>Niſi prius,</hi> or any tranſcript of Record, which the Records in the Treaſury, if it exceed not eight ſheetes xii. d. and if more, then after that rate, and for making and examining the Iurat. of every Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord of <hi>Niſi prius</hi> iiii. d. But whereas of late there hath been demanded and taken by the under Clarkes of that Office for the exemplifying of every Recovery with ſingle Voucher iiii. s. vi. d. and for exemplifying any other Record, not exceeding eight ſheetes, v. s. and for every ſheete more, vi. d. and for ingroſſing every Record of <hi>Niſi prius</hi> upon old iſſues for every ſheete iiii. d. We doe certifie that there are no ſuch Fees due unto them, And that the Fees due for thoſe Exemplifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations and Ingroſſements are ſatisfied and contained in the Fees certified by the Maſter of the ſaid Office.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="80" facs="tcp:66379:44"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Cryers</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>THe Fees mentioned in the Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate under the Cryers hands, We thinke are the uſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid during our remembrance, Except.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of ii. s. by them demanded for the calling of every Jury at the Bar when they fill not, the ancient Fee be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing but xii. d.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xvi. s. by them demanded for keeping of every Jurie during the ſitting of the Court, the ancient Fee being but iiii. s.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xxx. s. for keeping a Jury all night, the ancient Fee being but viii. s. and no more.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of vi. s. for every Attourney ſworne in Court, the ancient Fee be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing but iiii. s. and no more.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xii. d. for every baile ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken in Court, there being no Fee at all due unto them.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xii. d. for every Oath in Court, and for every <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>cir<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                              <desc>•••</desc>
                           </gap>c.</hi> called in Court, iiii. d. and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ii. d. for every Guardian admitted in Court, there being no ſuch Fees due unto them to our knowledges</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="81" facs="tcp:66379:44"/>As for the Fees of iiii. d. for every judgement, xii. d. for every finall judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, iiii. d. for every Nonſuit, viii. d. for every Fine, and viii. d. for every Recovery, We know no ſuch Fees due unto them, and they be the ſame which the Proclamator claimeth and hath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the Office of the keeper of the <hi>Treaſurie.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THe Fees mentioned in the certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate under the Keeper of the Treaſuries hand, We thinke to be all the uſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid during our re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membrance, Except,</p>
                     <p>IV. d. for a ſearch after three yeares, till ten yeares, nothing being due.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of vi. d. for every Roll car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried into Court, there being no ſuch Fee due, other then for a Plea Roll.</p>
                     <p>The ii. s. vi. d. for every Jury at Bar, xii. d. being only due, and no more to our knowledge.</p>
                     <p>The ii. s. vi. d. for a <hi>Niſi prius</hi> in Middleſex xii. d. only, and no more be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing there due.</p>
                     <p>The xviii. d. for his key after the Terme, xii. d. only being due.</p>
                     <p>And as for the Fee of iii. s. for making
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:66379:45"/>
up the Terme and Records vi. d. for every wager of Law, xviii. d. for a copy of a <hi>Precipe</hi> after the Terme, iiii. d. for a Fine acknowledged in the Treaſurie, and v. s. from the Clarke of the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurie for his attendance every Terme, we know not any of them to be due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>In the <hi>Outlarie</hi> Office.</head>
                     <p>THe Fees mentioned in the certifi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cate under the hand of Maſter At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourney generall for the Fees of the Clarke of the ſaid Office we ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge to be the uſuall and accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed Fees which have been paid du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring our remembrances.</p>
                     <p>But we doe certifie that under colour of theſe Fees, where there be more de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendants than one in a Writ, there is by them taken for the entrie of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſall to diſcharge proces thereupon, or upon a Writ of Error for every name, ii. s. viii. d. whereas we conceive there is but ii. s. viii. d. due for all in one Writ of Exigent, that be reverſed all one time.</p>
                     <p>Where there is demanded for ſearch of an Outlarie for every Terme within one yeare iiii. d. and for every Terme above the yeare, iii. d. we certifie it is
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:66379:45"/>
but only in caſe where ſearch is made by a ſtranger, and not by the Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies for Writs ſued out by themſelves.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Proclamators</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>THE Fees mentioned in the cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate under the hand of Maſter <hi>Senkey</hi> for the Fees of the Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mator, we thinke to be the uſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid to that Officer: But we certifie that the Prothonotaries, and the Chirogra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pher doe receive the ſaid Fees, and not that Officer himſelfe, which Fees are now claimed by the Cryers.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>Clarke of the Iuries.</head>
                     <p>AS for the Fees mentioned in the certificate of the Clarke of the Juries, under his hand we certifie they be the uſuall and accuſtomed Fees which have been paid ſince and during our remembrances.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="84" facs="tcp:66379:46"/>
                     <head>The Clarke of the <hi>Eſſoines.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Fees mentioned in the cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate under his hand, Wee thinke to bee the uſuall Fees which have been paid to that Officer during our remembrance.</p>
                     <p>The vi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. s. vi. d. demanded for exem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plifying of every Eſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>oine and Nonſuit thereupon, and iii. s. iiii. d. for the copy thereof, We know no ſuch Fee to be due unto him.</p>
                     <p>And as for the Fee of iiii. l. ix. s. by him demanded from the Officers of this Court, towards the numbring and marking of the Rolls every Terme, We know not any ſuch Fees due unto him, and if it be, We thinke it be not within our enquirie.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Court Keeper.</head>
                     <p>WHereas this Officer requireth ix. s. vi. d. for every Wager in Law, his due being onely xxii. d. the reſt is to be divided amongſt the Cryers, Wagermen, and other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, and for the ii. s. vi. d. for a Jurie at
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:66379:46"/>
Barre, we certifie that there is onely xii. d. due, and no more.</p>
                     <p>For the Fee of vi. s. viii. d. from the Clarke of the Treaſurie for hanging the Cloath of the Court, We know no ſuch Fee due to him, and if it be, it is from the Clarke of the Treaſury, and ſo under favour (as we conceive) not within our enquirie.</p>
                     <p>And as for the Fee of xii. d. for every Attourney ſworne in Court, ii. s. for a <hi>Niſi prius</hi> in Middleſex, iiii. d. for a Baile, iiii. d. for a Fine, iiii. d. for a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery at Barre, and ii. d. for ſatisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on acknowledged, We ſay there are no ſuch Fees due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Porters</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>THE Fees mentioned in the cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate under the Porters hand, We thinke are the uſuall and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed Fees during our remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brances paid, Except,</p>
                     <p>The Fee of v. s. for every triall at Barre, his due being but xii. d.</p>
                     <p>xii. d. for a <hi>Niſi prius,</hi> his Fee being but vi. d.</p>
                     <p>IV. d. for a Fine which is not to bee paid, but for every Fine acknowledged by a Feme covert in Court.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="86" facs="tcp:66379:47"/>IV. d. for every Writ of Entrie, iv. d. for a Baile, ii. d. for ſatisfaction ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged, and iiii. d. for a Guardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an, We certifie that there are no ſuch Fees due,</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Clarke of the <hi>Errors</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>FRom the now Clarke of Errors we have no certificate, but for the Fees formerly certified by Maſter <hi>Moile</hi> late Clarke of the Errors, we thinke that the Fees by him certified, are the Fees which uſually and accuſtomably paid during our remembrances, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept,</p>
                     <p>The Fee of iii. s. by him demanded for a <hi>Superſid. de non moleſtando,</hi> there being but ii. s. due, and ii. s. for making of the Record.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of ii. s. iiii. d. for a Nonſuit upon a Writ of Error, we certifie it is not due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="87" facs="tcp:66379:47"/>
                     <head>The Clarke of the <hi>Inrollments.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Fees certified by Maſter <hi>Iackman</hi> for the Fees of that Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, we certifie to be the Fees due by Stat. Except,</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xvi. d. by him demanded for ſearch of every Fine to be inrolled for every yeare, whereas the Fee by Stat. (as we conceive) is but iiii. d. a ſheete.</p>
                     <p>The Fee of xii. d. for copying every ſheete of every Fine inrolled, whereas the Fee (as we conceive) is but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iii. d. a ſheete.</p>
                     <p>And as for the Fee of viii. s. iiii. d. for the Clarkes Fee for inrolling by the Roll, and viii. s. iiii. d. for exemplify<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing after the ſame rate, and for the iii. s. iiii. d. for the rule upon amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, we doe certifie that we know no ſuch Fees to be due.</p>
                     <p>And as for the Fee of ii. s. demanded for retourning Writs of Covenant up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Fines, Writs of Entries, Summons and Seizins upon common Recoveries, as deputies of Record for Sheriffes ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Court, we doe certifie that the ſame Fee is not due unto him, but was anciently due and taken by</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="88" facs="tcp:66379:48"/>the Attournies, and allowed them for returning of the ſaid Writs, and their better care to avoide Errors in ſewing forth the ſaid Fines and Recoveries.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Attournies Fees.</head>
                     <p>VVEE doe certifie the Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies Fee for proſecution is, and during our remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance have been for every Terme it every reall action,</p>
                     <p>And in every other action<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>Bookes and Tables.</head>
                     <p>TOuching the having of any Bookes, Tables, Rolls, Orders, Warrants, Records, Entries, or other Notes, or writings for the diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of thoſe things we are charged with, Wee doe certifie that we have not any in our cuſtody, neither doe wee know where any are, but only in ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Offices by us certified.</p>
                     <pb n="89" facs="tcp:66379:48"/>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>
                           <list>
                              <item>Io: Nichols.</item>
                              <item>Peter Noyes.</item>
                              <item>Geo: Holland.</item>
                              <item>Roger Hide.</item>
                              <item>Rob: Hanſon.</item>
                              <item>Io: Wickeſteade.</item>
                              <item>Io: Bimbrone.</item>
                              <item>Io: Skinner.</item>
                              <item>Nich: Allen.</item>
                              <item>Fra: Kempe.</item>
                              <item>Io: Rowley.</item>
                              <item>Edw: Waller.</item>
                              <item>Io: Tyrer.</item>
                              <item>Roger Doddeſwell.</item>
                              <item>Rob. Benſon.</item>
                              <item>Will: Corfield.</item>
                              <item>Tho: Blofield.</item>
                              <item>Fra: Newbone.</item>
                              <item>Anth: Rogers.</item>
                              <item>Anth: Langſton</item>
                              <item>Geo: Needler.</item>
                              <item>Will: Cragge.</item>
                              <item>Peter Bird.</item>
                              <item>Edw: Ball.</item>
                              <item>Ro: Hamby.</item>
                              <item>Rich: Morſe.</item>
                           </list>
                        </signed>
Thus farre examined.</closer>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="part">
                  <pb n="90" facs="tcp:66379:49"/>
                  <argument>
                     <p>The Fees here under mentioned are the Fees due and paid to the Lord chiefe Iuſtice, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Iuſtices of the Court of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas at Weſtminſter, as they were due, and uſually paid to our Predeceſſors, Iuſtices of the ſame Court.</p>
                  </argument>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Lo: chiefe Juſtice his Fees.</head>
                     <p>FOR allowance of a Writ of Error upon an Outlarie before judgement,<note place="margin">xx. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Baile taken upon an Outlarie upon meane Proces in debt, if the debt be xx. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. or above,<note place="margin">ii. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the allowance of a writ of Error upon a judgement,<note place="margin">xx. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Baile taken in caſe of debt after judgement,<note place="margin">xii. s</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the allowance of a writ of Error
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:66379:49"/>
upon a judgement upon a <hi>Scire fac.</hi> and Outlarie after judgement,<note place="margin">xxxv. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For making the Roll that a writ of Error is allowed on,<note place="margin">ii. s. iii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a <hi>Superſid.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the tranſcript of a Record being a Proces,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d. 6. s. 8. d. 14. s. 9. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every proces more,</p>
                     <p>For the retourne of every <hi>Certiorar.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſeale of every Record of <hi>Niſi prius,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s. i. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſeale of every Writ ſealed in Court,<note place="margin">i. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſeale of every Exemplifica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,<note place="margin">ii. s. ii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <argument>
                        <p>The Fees following are due to ſuch of the Iudges who doe performe the buſineſſe.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr acknowledging of a Fine or warrant of Attorney for a common recoverie out of Court,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſigning every writ of priviledge, to remove any cauſe, <hi>Habeas corpus, procedendo,</hi> or <hi>Superſid.</hi> upon a <hi>Proce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dendo,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iv. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Baile taken out of Court upon any ſuch writ of priviledge, wherein one cauſe only is retourned,<note place="margin">ix. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="92" facs="tcp:66379:50"/>For every cauſe more,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the confeſſion of a judgement out of Court,<note place="margin">9. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Phillizers Baile, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Baile taken out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging ſatisfaction out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging out of Court a Deed to be inrolled,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For admiſſion of a Guardian out of Court,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the proofe of a ſuggeſtion out of Court, for every witneſſe,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a warrant for paſſing of a Fine, where there are more than three Cog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizors, or three Cognizees parties to the Fine,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Affidavit taken out of Court upon a forraigne Plea, or Reſcous,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For any other Affidavit taken out of Court,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For exhibiting of an Information out of Court,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſigning a Bill of coſts to award an Attachment for not appearing upon a <hi>Subpoena,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For granting a Licence to compound upon a penall Law,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For aſſeſſing of the Kings part of a forfeiture upon a penall Statute after compoſition with the Informer,<note place="margin">ii. s</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the commitment out of Court,
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:66379:50"/>
of a priſoner to the Fleete, charged with one cauſe only,<note place="margin">9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Baile taken out of Court upon an Outlarie in debt upon meane proces reverſed, if the ſame be xx. l.<note place="margin">ii. s. iv. d</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>
                        <hi>Divident</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Theſe Fees following are due to the Lord chiefe Iuſtice, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Iudges of the Court of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas, by way of Divident.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr confeſſing of a Judgement in Court,<note place="margin">vi<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For acknowledging ſatisfaction in court, if the debt or damage doe not amount unto 100. l.<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If the debt or damage doe amount to 100. l. xii. d. and for every 100. l. after the ſame rate,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For admitting an Infant in court to his Guardian,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For reverſing an Outlarie in Court for error in the Exigent, or retourne,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the like for the inſufficiency of the Proclamation, or retourne, or for
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:66379:51"/>
want of a Proclamation,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every common Recovery ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged in Court,<note place="margin">vi. d. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Fine acknowledged in Court,</p>
                     <p>For a Baile taken in Court, or a Baile or Recognizance acknowledged in Court,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a deed acknowledged in Court to be inrolled for a diſcontinuance,<note place="margin">xii. d. 9. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Prohibition granted,</p>
                     <p>For every wager of Law, or Nonſuit upon a wager of Law,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For admiſſion of an Attourney to be an Attourney of this court,<note place="margin">xx. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Puiſne</hi> Iudges Fees.</head>
                     <p>FOr every Fine drawne at the Bar,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Recovery drawne at the Barre with a ſingle Voucher,<note place="margin">xviii. d. vi. d. iiii. s. vi. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Voucher more,</p>
                     <p>For reverſall of an Outlary in court,</p>
                     <p>For taking of a privy Verdict,</p>
                     <p>For taxing of coſts upon every Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict,</p>
                     <p>From the Clarke of the Warrants every Terme, to every of the puiſne Judges,</p>
                     <p>For every Attourney, whoſe name is recorded in the Roll of Attournies eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Terme<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="95" facs="tcp:66379:51"/>For inrolling and examining the parts of a Fine, and Writs upon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Recoveries by the Stat. 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">vi. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Exemplification and exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of the parts of a Fine, and VVrits upon common Recoveries by that Stat.<note place="margin">v. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing and entring a rule for an amendment upon that Stat.<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a ſearch made upon the inroll<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment upon that Stat.<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a copie of a Fine, or Writs in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled upon common Recoveries in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled by that Stat. for every ſheete,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the retourne of every writ of Covenant brought to levy a Fine upon,<note place="margin">x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the retourne of every writ of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try to ſuffer a common Recovery, every writ of Summons and Seizin there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon,<note place="margin">x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>An ancient Fee of vi. s. viii. d. for ſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of a <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem</hi> due to the Judges of any Court who doe aſſigne the ſame, which is now, and of late hath been divided amongſt all the Judges that ride the Circuits,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="96" facs="tcp:66379:52"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Theſe Fees following are due to the Clarkes of the Lord chiefe Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, and other the Iuſtices of the ſaid Court.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>TO the Judges Clarke of the Fines, for taking of a Fine, or warrant of Attourney,<note place="margin">iii. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For certifying of a Fine, or retourne of a <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">xvi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>To the Judges Clarke of Bailes, for taking every Baile,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring every caveat to give no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice that good Baile may be taken,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ſatisfaction acknowledged out of Court,<note place="margin">xii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a Deed acknowledged out of Court to be inrolled,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the proofe of a ſuggeſtion out of Court for every witneſſe,<note place="margin">xii. d. iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For an Affidavit taken out of Court,</p>
                     <p>For entring into his Booke an Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation exhibited out of Court,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring into his Booke of coſts a warrant ſigned to award an attachment for not appearing upon a <hi>Subpoena,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="97" facs="tcp:66379:52"/>For entring into his booke a licence so compound upon a penall Law,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring into his booke the Kings part of the forfeiture upon a penall Law aſſeſſed by the Iudges, after com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition with the Informer,<note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring into a Booke, a commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment out of Court of a priſoner to the Fleete, charged with one cauſe only,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>To the puiſne Iudges Clarke of the Inrollments, for copying, inrolling, and examining the parts of a Fine, and Writs upon Recovery by the Statute, 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">8. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a ſearch made for an inroll<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment upon that Stat.<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For writing of a Fine, or Writs in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled upon a common Recovery in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled by that Stat.<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Tho: Richardſon.<lb/>
Ric: Hutton.<lb/>
Fra: Harvey<lb/>
Geo: Crooke.<lb/>
H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>n: Yel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>erton.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="part">
                  <pb n="98" facs="tcp:66379:53"/>
                  <head>FEBRVARII XVII. 1628.</head>
                  <div type="office">
                     <p>ACcording to an order of his Majeſties Commiſſioners for inquirie after exacted Fees, and innovated Offices, Wee whoſe names are hereunder ſubſcribed, have met and peruſed the Iudges Certificate of Fees to us delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by the ſaid Commiſſioners, which in our former preſentment or certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate we could not ſo exactly ſet downe, as we did the Officers Fees, for that we received from the Commiſſioners ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall certificates of the ſeverall Officers of the ſaid Court, concerning all their ſeverall Fees, but we then had not any certificate from the Iudges of their Fees by them demanded and certified,
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:66379:53"/>
but we now having received a certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate by the ſaid Commiſſioners from the ſaid Iudges, doe now this ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of February, 1628. upon due conſideration thereof had, certifie as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Lord chiefe Iuſtice his Fees.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>INprimis,</hi> Touching the xx. s. men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned by the Iudges certificate for allowance of a writ of Error, upon an Outlarie before judgement, or up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a writ of Error upon a judgement, which in our former certificate wee mentioned to be but xvii. s. vi. d. upon either of them, We certifie now, that for our reſpective knowledges there hath been paid in the whole xx. s. for every of the ſame, but we conceive ii. s. vi. d. thereof was for the Lord chiefe Iuſtice his Clarks, and only xvii. s. vi. d. for the Iudges.</p>
                     <p>Concerning the ii. s. iiii. d. for a Baile taken upon an Outlarie upon meane proces, the debt being xx. l. or above, mentioned in the Iudges certificate, we certifie that the ſame hath beene u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſually paid ſince an Order made by the Iudges concerning the putting in of a Baile into that caſe.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="100" facs="tcp:66379:54"/>Touching the xii. s. mentioned in the ſaid Certificate for a Baile taken in caſe of debt after judgement, we certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie that ſince the Stat<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> made for putting<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> in of Baile in that caſe, the ſame hat<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> been uſually paid.</p>
                     <p>Touching the ii. s. for marking the Roll the writ of Error is allowed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ii. s. for every <hi>Superſid</hi> We <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>rti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie the ſame hath been uſually paid to the Clarke of the Errors, but whether as due to the Iudge, or his Clarke, wee know not, yet ſome of the ancienteſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> men of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>y ſay, that there was an<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ciently paid for every ſuch <hi>Superſid</hi> but ii. s. as we formerly certified in our former Certificate under the title o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Fees of the Clarke of the Errors.</p>
                     <p>As to the Fee of ii. s. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> d<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> for the ſeale of every Record of <hi>Niſiprius,</hi> the ſame hath been ſo anciently paid, ſaying in caſe of Prop<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</p>
                     <p>Touching the Lord chiefe Iuſtice <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Fee of i. d. for the ſcale of every W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> ſealed in Court, and ii. d. for the ſeale of every Exemplification, we certifie them to be due, and parcell of the Fee of vii. d. and ii<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ii. d. certified in our former Certificate under the title of Fees of the Seale Office.</p>
                     <p>Touching the reſt of the Fees men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in the Iudges certificate to bee due to the Lord chiefe Iuſtice, wee
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:66379:54"/>
have uſually paid the ſame, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore doe think them to be due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The Fees due to ſuch of the Iudges as performe the buſineſſe.</head>
                     <p>TOuching the Fee of vi. s. viii. d. for the acknowledging of a Fine, or warrant of Attourney for a common Recovery out of Court, we certifie as formerly, that ix. s. viii. d. hath been uſually paid for the ſame in the whole, but (as we conceive) the Judge hath only vi. s. viii. d. and his Clarke the reſt.</p>
                     <p>Touching the ii. s. certified for an Affidavit taken out of Court upon a forreine Plea, or Reſcous, we certifie that the ſame hath been anciently paid, but how the ſame hath been anciently divided between the Judges and Clarks we know not.</p>
                     <p>Touching the viii. d. certified by the Judges of every other Affidavit taken out of Court, we doe certifie as in our former Certificate, that we have uſual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly paid xii. d. for the ſame, whereof we conceive iiii. d. is allowed to the Judges Clarkes, as appeareth by the Judges owne Certificate of their Clarkes Fees.</p>
                     <p>Touching the Fee for granting a
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:66379:55"/>
licence to compound upon a penall Law, we certifie as heretofore we have done, that anciently ii. s. vi. d. hath been uſed to be paid, whereof we con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive ii. s. due to the Judge, and vi. d. to his Clarke.</p>
                     <p>Touching the ix. s. viii. d. for every reverſall of an Outlarie out of Court, we certifie that uſually we have paid ſo much for one name, and if there have been more names than one in the writ, then for every other name ii. s.</p>
                     <p>Touching the ii. s. iiii. d. for Baile ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken out of Court upon an Outlarie in debt upon meane proces reverſed, if the debt be xx. l. or above, we certifie that ever ſince the order was made by the Court for putting in Baile in that caſe, the ſame hath been uſually paid.</p>
                     <p>Touching the iiii. s. certified for a warrant, for paſſing a Fine where there are more than three Cognizors, or three Cognizees parties to the Fine, we certifie that it hath been paid ever ſince the order made in that behalfe, as we have certified in our former Certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficate.</p>
                     <p>Touching the reſt of their Fees, wee certifie that we have uſually paid the ſame during our reſpective practiſes, and therefore thinke them to be due.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="103" facs="tcp:66379:55"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Divident</hi> Fees.</head>
                     <p>TOuching the Fee of xx. s. men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned to be paid for the admiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of every Attourney to be an Attourney of the ſame Court, we doe certifie that the ancient Fee was only ii. s. howſoever of late yeares xx. s. hath been paid, <hi>videlicet,</hi> for about ſixteen yeares.</p>
                     <p>Touching the reſidue of the Fees cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified by way of Divident, we doe cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie that we have uſually paid the ſame during our reſpective practiſes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>The <hi>Puiſne</hi> Iudges Fees.</head>
                     <p>TOuching the xii. d. certified for every Fine drawne at the Bar, and xviii. d. for every Recovery with a ſingle Voucher drawne at Bar, and vi. d. for every Voucher more, wee certifie the ſame to have been uſually paid to the hands of the ſaid Secon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daries.</p>
                     <p>Touching the xii. d. certified for taxing of coſts upon every judgement, we re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferre our ſelves to our former Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:66379:56"/>
in that behalfe made under the ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of the Prothonotaries.</p>
                     <p>Touching the xxxiii. s. for every puiſne Judge from the Clarke of the warrants, we ſay it paſſeth not through our hands<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> nor lyeth in our knowledge, but becauſe the Judges have certified it, we (knowing nothing to the contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry) thinke it to be due.</p>
                     <p>Touching the Fee of x. d. for retourne of every writ of Covenant brought to levie a Fine upon, x. d. for the retourn of every writ of Entrie to ſuffer a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Recovery, every writ of Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons and Seizms thereupon, we certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie as before we have done, under the title of the Clarke of the Inrollments, (whereunto we refer our ſelves) and conceive the ſame to be parcell of the ii. s. claimed by the Clarke of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rollments.</p>
                     <p>And touching the reſidue of the Fees certified to be due to the puiſne Judges only, we doe certifie that we have uſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally paid the ſame during our reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive practiſes, and therefore thinke them to be due.</p>
                     <pb n="105" facs="tcp:66379:56"/>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Subſcribed thus.
<list>
                              <item>Anth: Langſton.</item>
                              <item>Geo: Needler.</item>
                              <item>Fra: Kempe.</item>
                              <item>Edw: Waller.</item>
                              <item>Ro: Hyde.</item>
                              <item>Io: Rowley.</item>
                              <item>Roger Doddeſwell.</item>
                              <item>Ni: Allen.</item>
                              <item>Io: Skinner.</item>
                              <item>Io: Tyrer.</item>
                              <item>Io: Banbury.</item>
                              <item>Io: Wickeſteade.</item>
                              <item>Tho: Blofield.</item>
                              <item>Ro: Benſon.</item>
                              <item>William Cragge.</item>
                              <item>Peter Bird.</item>
                              <item>William Corefield.</item>
                              <item>Edw: Ball.</item>
                              <item>Ro: Hanſon.</item>
                              <item>Ro: Morſe.</item>
                              <item>Geo: Holland.</item>
                           </list>
                        </signed>
                        <signed>Ex. per me Iohan. Dibley Reg. Cle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ricum dic<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Commiſ.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:57"/>
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:57"/>
                  <p>A TABLE OF THE DVE FEES OF The Prothonotaries in THE COVRT OF the Commons PLEAS <hi>duodecimo Caroli Regis.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>London printed, 1641.</p>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div type="table_of_fees">
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:58"/>
                  <pb n="109" facs="tcp:66379:58"/>
                  <argument>
                     <p>Theſe are the Fees due and belon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the three Prothonotaries of the Court of common Pleas at Weſtm. for entries of Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>eas, and Iudgements. And alſo for making and entring of Writs in their ſeverall Offices, and for other dues belonging to them, confirmed and allowed by our So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraigne Lord King <hi>Charles,</hi> by his Letters Patents under the great Seale of England, dated at Cambury the 22. of Iuly, in the 12. yeare of his Raigne, and are men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned and expreſſed in a Schedule of Fees to the ſaid Letters annex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and recorded in his Maieſties Court of common Pleas at Weſtm. in the Terme of S. <hi>Michael</hi> next following, <hi>quinto, ſexto, ſeptimo, octavo, nono.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </argument>
                  <p>
                     <hi>INprimis,</hi> For the entry of every common Declaration, common Plea in Bar, wherein one Freehold is pleaded, common Replication, and Rejoynder in actions perſonall,</p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="110" facs="tcp:66379:59"/>For the entry of every ſpeciall De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration, ſpeciall Plea in Bar, or A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>batement Freehold Replication, or Rejoynder, and Pleas ſubſequent, in actions perſonall, not exceeding three ſheetes, every ſheete containing twelve lines at the leaſt, and every line con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining ten words,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete ſo exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For every Declaration in actions up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Caſe <hi>Ejectione firme,</hi> accompt, annuity, conſpiracy, covent, deceit, partition, <hi>Plegiis acquiet.</hi> and debt up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Statutes, plaint in Aſſize, and the like ſpeciall actions, and in reall mixt popular actions, if the declaration or plaint exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the entring of every Bar, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication, and Pleas ſubſequent in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the actions laſt above recited, and in the title actions, not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete ſo exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the buyer of every Bill, Obliga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Indenture, Record, or Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate, or the like, entred <hi>in haec verba,</hi> not exceeding the length of three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete above that length,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For recording of every apparance by the Court,<note place="margin">2. s. 4. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="111" facs="tcp:66379:59"/>For me entry of every Recognizance without condition, challenge to the Sheriffe or Coroners, or to the Aray, or other ſpeciall averments,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for the entring of every Recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance without a condition,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every judgement in Debt, Treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſe, or detinue, without a tales for the Prothonotary,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for entring of every adjourne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every Judgement with a Tales, beſides the Fee above recited,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every <hi>Remanet,</hi> and Judgement for coſt given to the Defendant by the Statute, beſides the Fee aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every judgement in all other actions, aſwell perſonall, as mixt, and reall, and prohibitions, and the like,<note place="margin">iv. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every Satisfaction, <hi>Recordatur,</hi> Diſcontinuance, <hi>Retraxit,</hi> Relinquiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, <hi>Nolle proſequi,</hi> or the like, in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions perſonall,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And in reall actions,</p>
                  <p>For the entry of a ſingle Recovery, and the writ of ſeiſm thereupon,<note place="margin">x. s. 6. d. vi. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every Voucher more,</p>
                  <p>For the entrance of a Summons <hi>ad Warr.</hi> for a common Recovery, and the writ of Summons <hi>ad Warr.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">iv. s. vi. s</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if for both,</p>
                  <p>For every forraigne Voucher ſent to the common Pleas to ſummon the
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:66379:60"/>
Vouchee, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>f the Record be not above three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete more,</p>
                  <p>The like Fees are to be paid when the Record is remitted back againe, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Voucher determined,<note place="margin">2. s. 8. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſpeciall Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict, whereupon a <hi>Cur. adviſar. vult</hi> is entred, being not above the length of three ſheetes, written as aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete exceeding that length,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every generall Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict, with a <hi>Cur. adviſar. vult,</hi> without a Tales,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And with a Tales,</p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Remittive of debt or damages,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Information upon any penall Law, and ſigning the <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ubpena</hi> only,<note place="margin">ii. s. 8. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entring of every ſurmiſe for a Prohibition to be granted, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding the length of three ſheetes, as aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete above that length,<note place="margin">viii <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of the Oath of every witneſſe to prove the ſurmiſe in a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibition, or <hi>Audita quercla</hi> brought by an <hi>Infant</hi> and the entry of the proofes <hi>de morte &amp; vita viri,</hi> dower, and the like actions in ſuits,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="113" facs="tcp:66379:60"/>For the releaſing of any default in any reall action,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And entring the recitall of the grand Cap.<note place="margin">iv. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For damages cleere in every action where damage is given, if the damage given amount to five markes or above, ii. s. in the pound,<note place="margin">ii. s. <hi>Nihil.</hi> xii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if under five markes,</p>
                  <p>For examining every record of <hi>N. i. pr.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>For making the Record for triall of an iſſue in any of the County Palatine, for the firſt three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete after,</p>
                  <p>For the exemplification of any Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord, not exceeding ſix ſheetes,<note place="margin">v. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete exceeding that rate,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entring of Seiſm in dower, &amp; dying ſeiſed, the retourn of the Seiſm, exceeding not above three ſheetes,<note place="margin">iiii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For entring of writs of Exemption <hi>de non ponend. in jurat.</hi> and Patents <hi>de libertat. elocand.</hi> and Protections, cog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance of Pleas, and the like, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the rates aboveſaid, if they ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the entring the default upon the diſtreſſe in waſt <hi>quar. imp.</hi> and the like, and judgement thereupon if the title or count doe not exceed three ſheetes,<note place="margin">6. s. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="114" facs="tcp:66379:61"/>And if it be more than as aforeſaid, for every ſheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entring of a <hi>Quo warranto,</hi> if it exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Plea thereup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, according to the ſame rate before,<note place="margin">ii. s. 8. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of a Plea of accompt pleaded before Auditors, if it be not above 3. ſheetes written as aboveſaid,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note> And if more, for every ſheet exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Summons, and Surveyance, and Pryor,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the admiſſion of an Infant to his <hi>Prochin amie,</hi> or Guardian,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if it be by Commiſſion,</p>
                  <p>For entring of the Defendants diſcharge upon a Cap. <hi>pro fine,</hi> or for a contempt,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the like upon Reſcous, retorned and admitted to his Fine,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For traverſing of a Reſcous, and iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue thereupon,<note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entring of the allowance of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry generall and ſpeciall Pardon of<note place="margin">5. s. 4. d.</note> Outlarie before judgement, and after</p>
                  <p>For entring of a <hi>Dies dat.</hi> in debt, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue, and treſpaſſe,<note place="margin">xi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. d. ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And in all other actions,</p>
                  <p>For the entring of the receipt of a feme Covert, Tenant in taile, Leſſee for yeares, or the like,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for the entry of the Plea, if it ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete exceeding,</p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="115" facs="tcp:66379:61"/>And if the receipt be by writ, then more for entring of the writs,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entring of an Aſſize deliver in the Common Pleas by Juſtices of Aſſize to be inrolled for every ſheete,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if the Aſſize come into the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Pleas by <hi>Certiorar.</hi> then more for entring the <hi>Certiorar.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entring every abridgement of the demaundant in dower Aſſize, or the like,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every <hi>pone</hi> to remove a Plea by writ out of the County Court there holden by Juſtices, and for the retourne of the <hi>Pone,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entring of any Record ſent in the Common Pleas by <hi>Mittimus,</hi> or otherwiſe; and likewiſe for the entry of every <hi>Rege inconſulto,</hi> or ſuch like,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note> if it exceed not three ſheetes,</p>
                  <p>For every ſheete ſo exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the entring of every Certificate of Baſtardy certified by the Biſhop, and the awarding of the writ and judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereupon,<note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of the Licence of the Court, to purchaſe a new writ by Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies accompts,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Originall writ delivered of Record in reall mixt actions,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſheete above three ſheetes of every challenge to the
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:66379:62"/>
Sheriffe or Coroners, or to the Aray or other ſpeciall averments, or the like,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every <hi>Remanet</hi> in reall actions,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every <hi>Remittitur</hi> in reall and mixt actions,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſheete above three ſheetes of every aide pryer,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of an admiſſion of a Guardian, if it be by Commiſſion and <hi>Mittimus,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">vi. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of a privy Seale for every ſheete,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of the Licence of the Court to compound upon penall Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entry of every warrant of Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney made by the Tenant in the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Recoveries, or the like, after their appearance at the Bar<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For every Judgement by ſpeciall Commiſſion of the title in <hi>Quare imp.</hi> or the like, if it exceed not three ſheets,<note place="margin">iiii. s. iiii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete after,</p>
                  <p>For the entring of every ſpeciall im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parlance,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entring of every Committitur of a Priſoner by the Roll, being brought to the Bar by writ, and every <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ender of the body in diſcharge of the Baile,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>But if it be without writ, then in ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Caſe but,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="117" facs="tcp:66379:62"/>For entring of every demaund of a priſoner to appeare and remaund the ſaid priſoner,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Eſſoine in the Plea Rolls, as upon wagers of Law,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entry of the Baile upon every Reverſall for inſufficiency of Exigent, or of the Retourne,<note place="margin">2. s. 4. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every Declaration in debt upon demiſe, or the like ſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all Declaration, if the Declaration ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if ſuch Declaration exceed the number of three ſheetes, then for the entry of every ſuch ſheete, containing twelve lines, and every line tenne words,<note place="margin">viii. d</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſeverall Count in actions upon the Caſe and Accompt, and the like upon ſeverall daies, if the Accompt exceed not three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete ſo exceeding,</p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſeverall Count upon an originall Debt, Deti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue, Treſpaſſe, and the like,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſpeciall con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, or indorſement of any obligati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on entred <hi>in haec verba,</hi> not exceeding the length of three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete ſo exceeding,</p>
                  <p>But if the condition be in debt for paiment of money at one day, or under
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:66379:63"/>
the length of two ſheetes, then for the<note place="margin">xii. d.</note> entring thereof but</p>
                  <p>For the entry of every <hi>Mittimus,</hi> or <hi>Certiorar.</hi> and the Retourne thereof,<note place="margin">iiii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>But if the Retourne thereof exceed three ſheetes, then for every ſheete ſo exceeding,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For entring of the Count in a Prohi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition, and pleadings thereupon after an appearance of the Defendant, not exceeding the length of three ſheetes,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete above that length,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of every writ of Attaint or falſe judgement,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the entry of the Retourne thereof and the aſſignement of Errors, or falſe Oathes, not exceeding three ſheetes,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for every ſheete more,</p>
                  <p>For the entry of every ſheete above three ſheetes of the Oath of every wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe examined to prove the ſurmiſe in a Prohibition, or <hi>Audita querela</hi> brought by an Infant, and the entry of the proofes <hi>De morte &amp; vita viri</hi> in dower, and the like actions and ſuits,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                  </p>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="119" facs="tcp:66379:63"/>
                     <argument>
                        <p>Fees due to the <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> for <hi>Writs,</hi> and the <hi>Entries</hi> of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                           </gap> amongſt other dues.</p>
                     </argument>
                     <p>FOr every Writ of Prohibition or conſultation, not exceeding four ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s. iiii<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> d<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Writ ſo exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For every Withernam return <hi>habend.</hi> after appearance, ſecond de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverance, Writ of priviledge, <hi>habeas corpus. procedend. certiorare,</hi> Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons and Reſummons, <hi>Pete, cape, ve. fac. ſci. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>a. Elegit, extent. ſuperſs. Sub pena</hi> Writ to the Biſhop, Attachment in Aſſ. <hi>Diſtringas Iu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. habeas corpus,</hi> and <hi>Diſtringas</hi> in Aſſ. <hi>&amp; Attaint,</hi> and the like <hi>hab<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>re Fac. poſſeſſionem,</hi> Writs of view, <hi>mittimus, Idemptitat. habeas,</hi> and every other ſpeciall Writ.<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring of ſuch other Writ, which requireth an entring not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding four ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if more, for every ſheet exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as aboveſaid,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="120" facs="tcp:66379:64"/>For every <hi>Ca. fa. &amp; fi. fa.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Teſtat. fur. ca. fa. &amp; fi. fa. diſtringas ad deliberand.</hi> and Writs to enquire of damages in treſpaſſes and Replevin,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Writs to enquire of damages in Covenant, Ejectment, Actions up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the caſe, and the like,<note place="margin">ii. s. vi. d. x. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Capias pro fine,</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the <hi>Exigent,</hi> for a <hi>Capias pro fine.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entry of the Returne of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Writ in the Prothonotaries <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>oll other than the <hi>Ca. fa.</hi> returnd <hi>non eſt invent.</hi> and the <hi>fi. fa.</hi> returnd <hi>nulla ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bet bon<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi> whereupon further proceſſe is awarded not exceeding four ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if more, then for every ſheet.</p>
                     <p>For the entring of every ſheet of Priviledge or <hi>habeas corpus,</hi> with the Bayl for one cauſe,<note place="margin">vi. s<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every name more,</p>
                     <p>For entry of every <hi>Committitur</hi> upon a <hi>Habeas corpus una cum die &amp; cauſa,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every other cauſe,</p>
                     <p>For every Reverſall upon an Outla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry for default of Proclamation with one name, and the Bayl o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>nolle pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequi,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">4. s. 4. d. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every name more,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>ca. fa. &amp; fi. fa.</hi> after a <hi>devaſtavit,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Whereof by allowance from the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thonotaries the Clerke hath had,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="121" facs="tcp:66379:64"/>For every ſheet exceeding four ſheets of Writs to enquire of Damages in Covenant, Ejectment, Actions upon the caſe, and the like Actions,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Writ of Liberate, or the like ſpeciall Writ,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Whereof by allowance from the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thonotary the Clerke hath had,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entry of every ſuch Writ and the entry of every other ſpeciall Writ which requireth an entry not exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing four ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s. viii. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheet ſo exceeding,</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Diſtringas</hi> in petition,</p>
                     <p>Whereof the Clerke by allowance from the Prothonotary hath had,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For Writs to enquire of damages in Covenant, Ejectiment, Actions upon the caſe, and the like Actions if they ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed not four ſheets,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Whereof by allowance from the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thonotary the Clerke hath had,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entry of every <hi>Committitur,</hi> upon <hi>habeas corpus una cum die &amp; cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſa</hi> with one cauſe returned beſides the entry of the Writ,<note place="margin">ii. s. ii. s. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for the entry of the writ,</p>
                     <p>And for every other cauſe returned, For the ſigning of all proceſſe upon information, excepting the firſt <hi>Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pena,</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="122" facs="tcp:66379:65"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Clarkes fees.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>IMprimis,</hi> for the copies of common declaration and pleas for every ſheet conteining twelve lines, and every line ten words,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſheet in Reall and mixt Actions, and Actions upon any Statute and the like,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing of every ſpeciall decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration and plea, for every ſheet,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every continuance every Terme of every iſſue writ, <hi>imperlance demurrer</hi> or ſpeciall verdict or adjornment,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For exemplifying every Recovery with a ſingle voucher,<note place="margin">4. s. 6. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For exemplifying of a double vou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cher,<note place="margin">vi. s. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every voucher more,</p>
                     <p>For exemplifying of any Record not exceeding eight ſheets,<note place="margin">v. s. vi. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for every ſheet more,</p>
                     <p>For drawing of every extraordinary long writ after the rate for every ſheet,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for the entry thereof (if it ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire) for every ſheet,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a copy of a judgement for every ſheet,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entry of every writ, and the returne thereof into the Prothonotaries
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:66379:65"/>
Remembrance for drawing up of a<note place="margin">vi. d. iiii. d.</note> judgement if it exceed not three ſheets.</p>
                     <p>And for every ſheet after,</p>
                     <p>For entring of every Common Rule into the Bill of Pleas or Common Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membrance,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring and ingroſſing eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Summons for a Recovery and for the making of the writ of Summons,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entry of every <hi>Mittimus</hi> and <hi>Dedimus poteſtatem</hi> for a Recovery,<note place="margin">ii. s. 6. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ingroſſing of every <hi>Niſi priùs</hi> after the rate for every ſheet,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of every <hi>Teſtat. ſur. ca. fa. &amp; ſi. fa.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the ſearch of one Terme in the Prothonotaries office in his d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ggets or Remembrances,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the iſſuing out of the Court mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney if the party receiving it,<note place="margin">i. d. <hi>in</hi> 
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the making of every long writ as Prohibitions &amp; the like for every ſheet,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the proſecution and iſſuing out of proces for the King to bring in the party for to make fine for his contempt untill the party render himſelfe o bee<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note> outlawed beſides the fees of the Court,</p>
                     <p>And if there becauſe of Proſecution after the <hi>Exigent</hi> returned then more,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copies of ſuggeſtion to grant a Prohibition for every ſheet,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing of every ſurmiſe to have a Prohibition ſpeciall verdict, and the<note place="margin">viii. d.</note> like, for every ſheet.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="124" facs="tcp:66379:66"/>
                     <head>The <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Clerkes fees for Informations onely.</head>
                     <p>FOr engroſſing of every informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        <note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For a copy of the ſaid Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion if it amount to the number of five ſheets of paper, or upwards,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If it be under the number of five ſheets, then for every ſheet,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the making of every <hi>Capias pro<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fine</hi> upon an Information,<note place="margin">vi. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of the generall iſſue up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Roll where the information was firſt entred in the Terme it was firſt exhibited,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the Regiſtring of every licence to compound in the office book.<note place="margin">iiii. d</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <head>An ancient fee due to the ſecond <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> Clerks onely.</head>
                     <p>FOr recording of every Fine ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged at the Bar, writ and moved by a ſergeant.<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="125" facs="tcp:66379:66"/>
                     <head>Fees due to the Secondaries of the <hi>Prothonotaries</hi> in their ſeverall offices.</head>
                     <p>FOr the copy of every common Rule,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For taking a note of the Rule of the judges in Court upon the motion of a ſergeant for drawing the ſame Rule in paper in Latin words and entring it into the Bill of Pleas and the copy thereof the draught not exceeding ſix lines in paper,<note place="margin">viii. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If the Rule exceed ſix lines then,</p>
                     <p>For every wager in law in Court or Nonſuit of the plaintife, upon a wager of law,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entry of the <hi>Committitur</hi> of any defendant to the <hi>Fleet</hi> in execution of any judgement or otherwiſe in Court and for making a copy thereof for the Warden of the <hi>Fleet</hi> containing the cauſe of the Commitment,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the entring of every Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to the <hi>Fleet</hi> of any perſon yeeld<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing himſelfe in diſcharge of his Baile and for the like Copy,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For attending him from his chamber to <hi>weſtminſter</hi> to take a privy verdict cried at the Bar,<note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="126" facs="tcp:66379:67"/>For reading the Record of a demurrer in Court or verdict,<note place="margin">xii. d. xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For taking Bail in Court,</p>
                     <p>For entring of an admiſſion of an infant to his prochin Amy or Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian in the Prothonotaries remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the copy of the iſſue and jurors names to be delivered to the jury upon any triall at the Ba<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For reading of evidences upon trials at the Bar of each party plaintiffe and defendant,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entring of every ſatisfaction by ſpeciall warrant <hi>Recordatur</hi> and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>continuance,<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſatisfaction by generall warrant,<note place="margin">iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For entry of every Bill or Letters of Adminiſtration to enable an Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutor or Adminiſtrator to acknowledge ſatisfaction and the entry of the ſatiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction,<note place="margin">xii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every copy of Interrogatories, depoſitions of perſons examined upon Interrogatories by order of the Court for every ſheet.<note place="margin">viii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Per b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>eve de Privato ſigillo, wolſeley.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </div>
                  <div type="office">
                     <pb n="127" facs="tcp:66379:67"/>
                     <head>A Table of the Fees due unto the Six-Clarkes of the Kings Court of Chancery.</head>
                     <p>FOr all firſt, ſecond, or other Copies of all Bils, Anſwers, and other pleadings whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, as alſo of all Certificates, and Examinations made or ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken by vertue of any Commiſſion out of this Court, and of the interrogato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries therewith retourned, and alſo of all Declarations, or proceedings by Engliſh Bill, or according to the courſe of the common Law, and for co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies of Records, Rolls, or Evidences brought in to be copied, or remaining in the ſaid Court, for every leafe of<note place="margin">viii. d.</note> paper containing fifteen lines,</p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of all Warrants, whereby any Patents, Commiſſions, Licenſes, Pardons, Leaſes, or other Graunts whatſoever doe paſſe by, and under the great Seale, after the rate for every skin ſo paſſing the great Seale,<note place="margin">xx. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="128" facs="tcp:66379:68"/>For the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nrolling of all warrants for all Commiſſions of peace for Gaole de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livery, for a liberty for Oyer and Ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miner, for Piracies for the preſervation of the game of Swans, and for Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions of enquiry ſued out for the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of any private perſon, for every of the ſaid Commiſſions.<note place="margin">xx. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of all Warrants for all Commiſſions of appeale, and for the Admiralty, for every one of them,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of every warrant, for every ordinary Licence, or pardon of alienation,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>But if it bee of more then ordinary length, then according to the length, after the rate of xx. s. the skin, and not above.</p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of all Warrants for all Commiſſions in the nature of Writs of <hi>Diem clauſit extremum man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>damus devenerunt, qu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> plura ideotae proband. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>unatico inquirend. melius in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quirend.</hi> for every of them,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of the warrants for every Patent or graunt of the cuſtody of any Ward,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of the warrants for every preſentation, donation, or revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation to any Rectory, Vicaridge, Deanery, Archdeanery, Chancellor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip,
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:66379:68"/>
Treaſurerſhip or dignity to any Metropoliticall, Cathedrall, or Colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giat Church, or for any Canonſhip, or Prebend in any of the ſaid Churches, or for the Maſterſhip of any Hoſpitall, or other Eccleſiaſticall living, or for the grant of any preſentation, or pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentations <hi>pro unica vel pluribus vici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus</hi> thereunto,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of the warrants for every <hi>Mandamus ad inſtalland.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of all warrants for all Licenſes for Wines for every life,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>Or ſuch Fee not exceeding that pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion, as by the Lord Chancel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, or Lord Keeper ſhall be ſet downe, and by an order lately made by the right Honourable the Lord Keeper that now is, there is but vi. s. viii. d. paid, although it be granted for their lives, or more.</p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of the warrants for every pardon of Outlawrie,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrolling of the warrants for every denization, or commiſſion of Bankrupts,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the writing of every Exemplifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, aſwell of Records in the Tower as of any Record whatſoever, being in their cuſtody after the rate of every skin,<note place="margin">26. s. S. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="130" facs="tcp:66379:69"/>Of every Client for every Terme hileſt his cauſe dependeth, undeter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined by decree, or diſmiſſion, the termely fee of<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>If there be twenty Plaintifes or more in one Bill, they all pay but one Fee for one Terme,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>But for every three Defendants ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counting the husband and the wife, but for one perſon there is the Fee of iii. s. iiii. d. due for their firſt appearance.</p>
                     <p>And upon the firſt appearance, if every Defendant appeare ſeverally by himſelfe, he is to pay the fee of iii. s. iiii. d. but every Terme afterwards du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the continuance of the cauſe, there is only the Fee of iii. s. iiii. d. the terme to be paid for all the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants that appeared in any Terme or Vacation before in the ſame cauſe.</p>
                     <p>For every Attachment, and attach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment with Proclamation, which is made in their offices, aſwell renewed as o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, unleſſe the renovation grow by occaſion of the default of the Clarke,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every commiſſion of rebellion renewed, or otherwiſe, unleſſe the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>novation be by the like default of the Clarke,<note place="margin">viii. s. ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the inrollment thereof,</p>
                     <p>And for the inrollment of every com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion of Rebellion iſſuing out of the Court of Starchamber,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="131" facs="tcp:66379:69"/>For the inrollment of every liberate and allocate,<note place="margin">3. s. 4. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Commiſſion aſwell renew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, as other, to take an anſwer to heare and determine, or to examine witneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes either beyond the Seas, or in any place or part whatſoever of England, Scotland, or Wales, unleſſe the reno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation be occaſioned by ſome defect in the former Commiſſion, occaſioned by the default of the Clarke, and not of the Client, the ſumme of<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if the Commiſſion to examine witneſſes bee joynt, then to each at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d. 6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if it be <hi>ex parte,</hi> then but one,</p>
                     <p>For every Commiſſion upon any or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the Court, aſwell renewed as other, unleſſe the enovation be by the like default of the Clarke,<note place="margin">x. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every writ of Execution upon any Order,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For ingroſſing every Bill in Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery hand, wherein anſwer is to bee made by Commiſſion, for every leafe,<note place="margin">vi. d. xxxiii. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> &amp; iiii. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For drawing and inrolling of every decree and diſmiſſion reſpectively,</p>
                     <p>And neither they, nor their Clarkes to take any further Fees.<note place="margin">xxvi. s. &amp; viii. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every writ of Execution upon a Decree, after the rate for every skin,</p>
                     <p>For the writing of every Sheriffes patent, and for the writ of aſſiſtance,
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:66379:70"/>
writ of Diſcharge, commiſſion to take the Sheriffes oathes, the Attournies Fee, as alſo for the warrant of Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nie, and the writing of the two oathes,<note place="margin">30. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>And for the ten divided Counties mentioned in the acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment made in 8. <hi>&amp; 13. Eliz.</hi> to cleare all future miſtakings or doubts, they ſhall for the time to come take but halfe ſo much as for other Counties whatſoever hath been uſed heretofore, and neither they, nor their under-Clarkes are to take by any colour any other Fee for Sheriffes Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents then aforeſaid.</p>
                     <p>The like Fees for every Engliſh Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheator, ſaving for the warrant of At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney,<note place="margin">30. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For the drawing and ingroſſing of every Injunction, the Fee,<note place="margin">13. s. 4. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>But the inrolling of Injunctions is of little uſe, and needleſſe, except only in ſpeciall Caſes, when the Court ſhall appoint them to bee inrolled, and then it is to be done without any new Fee.</p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Superſid.</hi> for the diſcharge of any commiſſion, or other writ made
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:66379:70"/>
in any of the ſix Clarkes offices,<note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every <hi>Superſid.</hi> of priviledge, <hi>pro venientibus vel redeuntibus ad vel a Cancellar.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">6. s. 8. d</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every ſpeciall <hi>Certiorar.</hi> or <hi>pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cedendo corpus cum cauſa,</hi> or <hi>habeas corpus,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">6. s. 8. d.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every baile upon every writ of <hi>corpus cum cauſa,</hi> or matter of privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For all manner of <hi>Certiorar.</hi> and <hi>pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cedend.</hi> of courſe,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>For every Recogniſance or Bond made to the Court,<note place="margin">ii. s.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>The ſix Clarkes are to preſent their Clients cauſes which are to bee heard either in Court, or at the Rolls, but neither they nor their under Clarkes, nor any other are to take any fee or reward at all therefore, but to reſt content with their Fees allowed in this table of Fees.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="ordinances">
                  <pb n="134" facs="tcp:66379:71"/>
                  <argument>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ordinances</hi> made by <hi>Thomas</hi> Lord Coventry, Lord Keeper of the great Seale of England, with the adviſe and aſſiſtance of the right honourable Sir <hi>Iulius Caeſar.</hi> Knight, Maſter of the Rolls, in the Terme of S. <hi>Michael</hi> the Archangel, in the eleventh year of the raigne of our Soveraigne Lord King <hi>Charles,</hi> for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſſe of ſundry Errors, Defaults and Abuſes in the high Court of Chancery, 17. <hi>Novemb.</hi> 1635.</p>
                  </argument>
                  <p n="1">1. THat Bills, Anſwers, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plications, and Rejoyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders bee not ſtuffed with repetition of Deeds, or writings <hi>in haec verba,</hi> but the effect and ſubſtance of ſo much of them only as is pertinent and materiall to be ſet downe, and that in effectuall and briefe termes, that long and need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:66379:71"/>
traverſes of points not traverſable, nor materiall, cauſeleſſe recitals, tau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tologies, and multiplication of words, and all other impertinencies occaſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing needleſſe prolixity be avoided, and the ancient brevity and ſuccinctneſſe in Bils, and other pleadings reſtored, and upon any default herein the party and counſell under whoſe hand it paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth, ſhall pay the charge of the copie, and be further puniſhed as the caſe ſhall merit.</p>
                  <p n="2">2. When the Defendants have an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered the Plaintiffes, and their coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſell are ſeriouſly to adviſe of the an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers, and if they finde that upon the anſwer alone, without further proofe, there be ſufficient ground for an or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der or decree to proceed upon the an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer without further lengthening the cauſe, or if it be needfull to prove one or a few particular points to reply un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to thoſe points, and not to draw into pleading, or proofes any more than thoſe neceſſary points, thereby making long bookes, and putting both ſides to unneceſſary charges, the defaulters herein to be puniſhed by paying the charge of the copies, or otherwiſe, as the cauſe ſhall require.</p>
                  <p n="3">3. That interrogatories for exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning witneſſes be drawne only upon points materiall, and not upon matters
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:66379:72"/>
which are either conſeſſed in the plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, or are impertinent and needleſſe to be proved, That the articles which are uſually thruſt into the beginning of every Schedule of interrogatories, as it were of forme or courſe, touching the witneſſes knowledge of parties, plaintiffes or defendants of the lands, towns, &amp; places in the pleadings, and the like, be not ſo needleſly uſed as they are, but if for croſſe examining any witneſſe, or for other ſpeciall reaſon, it ſhall be neceſſary to miniſter any ſuch queſtion, every man is left at liberty to doe therein as much as ſhall be perti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent and needfull in a d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e and ſitting place, and if any ſhall offend againſt this, the party and ſuch as drew the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terrogatories ſhal be puniſhed by pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as much as the other ſide is by that meanes over-charged in copies, and further as the caſe ſhall merit.</p>
                  <p n="4">4. When the parties are at iſſue, and doe proceed to examination of witneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s either in Court, or by Commiſſion, as the interrogatories are to be perti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent and materiall, ſo the witneſſes are to be ſorted by thoſe that produce them, that they may be examined upon ſuch interrogatories as are proper and ſit for them, and not to examine a multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude of witneſſes upon a multitude of queſtions altogether unknown to them,
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:66379:72"/>
as it is too frequently done upon paine that where any groſſe abuſe or default herein ſhall bee made appeare to the Court, the defaulter ſhall pay as much as the other ſide is by that meanes over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged in copies, and ſhall be further puniſhed if the Court ſee cauſe.</p>
                  <p n="5">5. When a Commiſſion is awarded to examine witneſſes, if by the default of him that hath the carriage of the Commiſſion or his Commiſſioners no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing is done, he ſhall beare all the charge that the other ſide was put unto about that Commiſſion, either for Fees of Court, bringing, or entertaining Commiſſioners or witneſſes, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe to be aſcertained by the oath of the party, or of him that disburſed the money for him, and ſhall renew the Commiſſion at his own charges.</p>
                  <p n="6">6. When a Commiſſion is awarded to examine witneſſes, and the one ſide produceth and examineth all his wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes, and the other ſide doth not, but pray a new Commiſſion, if it be grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, he ſhall beare as the charge of the renewed Commiſſion both in Court and in the Countrey, as well for the charge and entertainment of his owne Commiſſion, as of the Commiſſioners of the other ſide, and the other ſide ſhal be permitted to croſſe examine the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes produced by him that reneweth
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:66379:73"/>
the Commiſſion, but if he will examine any other witneſſes of his owne, then he ſhall beare his owne part of the charge, the charges herein mentioned to be aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>certained by the oath of the party, or of him that disburſed the money for him.</p>
                  <p n="7">7. He at whoſe inſtance a Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion to examine witneſſes after a for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Commiſſion executed and return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed is once renewed, and he by whoſe default, or by default of his Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners a former Commiſſion was not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecuted, and thereupon it is renewed, ſhall at his perill examine all his wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes by that renewed Commiſſion, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> examine them in Court by the end of the Terme wherein that renewed Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion is retournable, without any more, or further delay.</p>
                  <p n="8">8. When witneſſes are examined in Court upon a Schedule of interrogato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, there ſhall be no new interrogato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie put in to examine the ſame witneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, but the witneſſes ſhall be examined only upon ſuch interrogatories as were exhibited before the witneſſes to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amined were ſworne, neither ſhall any witneſſes be examined in Court after the day of publication, though they were ſworne before, ſo as a copie of the rule of publication be delivered to the examiner, whereby he may take know ledge of the publication.</p>
                  <p n="9">
                     <pb n="139" facs="tcp:66379:73"/>9. When witneſſes are examined in Court, they ſhall perfect and ſubſcribe their depoſitions unto ſuch interroga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tories as they have anſwered before they depart from the Examiner, or his deputy, and ſhall not be permitted to make any alterations thereof at any time after, without leave of the Court, unleſſe it be in ſome circumſtance of time, or the like, or for making perfect of a ſumme upon view of any deed, booke, or writing which the witneſſes ſhall ſhew to the Examiner, before hee admit of ſuch alteration.</p>
                  <p n="10">10. The ſix Clarkes who are the on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Attournies in this Court, ought to informe themſelves continually of the ſtate and proceedings of their Clients Cauſes, whereby they may be able to defend their Clients, and to give ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count to the Court as the Attournies in all other Courts doe, and not to leave the care and knowledge thereof upon their under Clarkes who attend not in Court, and the Clients and ſuch as follow their Cauſes are to acquaint their Attournies for that purpoſe.</p>
                  <p n="11">11. Such as deſire to have their Cauſes ſet downe for hearing, muſt re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paire to the ſix Clark that is Attourney in the Cauſe, at leaſt ſix daies before the end of the Term, that the ſix Clark may inform himſelfe of the ſtate of the
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:66379:74"/>
cauſe of the long or ſhort dependance thereof in Court of the antiquity of publication of the weight or value of the cauſes, and all other circumſtances materiall, to informe the Lord Keeper, or the Maſter of the Rolls at the time of ſetting downe of cauſes, and the ſix Clark may not refuſe to offer the ſame to be ſet downe, if he be attended in ſuch due time as aforeſaid, nor come unprepared to inform the Lord Keeper or Maſter of the Rolls of the nature &amp; circumſtance of the cauſe aforeſaid, and neither he, nor any of his under-Clarkes, nor any other are to take any Fee, Gratuity, or Reward for the ſame.</p>
                  <p n="12">12. The Regiſters in drawing up Orders ſhall uſe all convenient brevi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty according to the manner of ancient times, they ſhall mention the materiall Reports, Affidavits, and former Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders upon which any new Order is grounded to have been read, but ſhall not repeat the ſame, they ſhall not un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe it be by ſpeciall direction of the Court, fill any Order with the diſputes of Councell, nor with reaſons and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>legations <hi>pro &amp; con,</hi> nor mention any reaſons but ſuch on which the Court relyed in making the Order, and thoſe with brevity and cleareneſſe, and if they deliver a draught or copie of any Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:66379:74"/>
to be peruſed by Councell, if it be not brought back within 24. houres, they ſhall enter the Order without at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending any longer for an anſwer from Councell, only they ſhall forbeare the entries of Decrees and diſmiſſions, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till they be ſigned, that the Lo: Keeper and the Maſter of the Rolls may re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forme them, if there be cauſe at the ſigning.</p>
                  <p n="13">13. Whereas the exceſſive and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neceſſary length and charge of writs <hi>de executione decreti</hi> have been com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained of, from henceforth unleſſe the party that ſueth out ſuch Writ ſhall de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that the whole Decree as it is ſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and inrolled be therein recited, the writ, if it be only for paiment of money ſhall make no other recitall but to this or the like effect, <hi>Cum per quoddam Decretum in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ur<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Cancellar. noſtr. die Ann<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>egni noſtri ordinat. &amp; adjudicatum exiſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>t quod tu ſolveres A. B. centum l b. legal. monetae Angl. t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> praec p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>mus &amp; fir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>er injungend. mandamus quod praed. centum l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>b. praefat. A. B. debit. mod<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſolvas et hoc nullatenus om<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ttas periculo incumbente.</hi> And if the money by the Decree be payable at certaine daies, or places, then the ſame daies and places to be expreſſed in the Writ without any further recitall, and if the Decrees bee
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:66379:75"/>
for doing other things to be performed by the party or parties to whom the ſaid Writ is directed, then no more ſhall be recited in the Writ but the very decre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tall order, unleſſe the decretall order doe in ſuch manner refer to a Report, or Certificate, as without recitall of thoſe points of the Report, or Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate which are to be performed by the parties to whom the ſaid Writ is dire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, it will not appeare what is to bee by them performed, and in that caſe ſo much of the Report, or Certificate as is to be performed by the ſaid parties ſhall be recited, and the order con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firming the ſame, and no more unleſſe it be deſired by the party ſuing out the ſaid Writ, and the Fee thereof to bee paid, ſhall be after the rate preſcribed in the table of Fees, and no more.</p>
                  <p n="14">14. Every demurrer ſhall containe the cauſes of the demurrer, and the Counſell who ſet their hands to it, are to beware that thoſe cauſes be not tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viall, and where a demurrer or plea is grounded upon the ſubſtance and the body of the matter, it ſhall be deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined in open Court without refe<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rence, and the Regiſter at the inſtance of the party demurring, ſhall without any Fee put into the paper of cauſes after the hearing and aſſigning a ſpee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy day to every one in order, as hee
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:66379:75"/>
commeth to require it, and if the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant who demurred make no ſuch inſtance to the Regiſter within eight daies after the plea and demurrer is put in Court, the ſame without any motion ſhall be diſallowed of courſe as put in for delay, and the Defendant ſhall pay ordinary coſts, provided that the Regiſter doe not without ſpeciall warrant put above two of thoſe demur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers into the paper upon one day.</p>
                  <p n="15">15. If the demurrer be grounded only upon ſome error, ſlip, or miſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king in the Bill, no Reference ſhall be made thereof for a week after it comes in, but the Plaintife without any moti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſhall be admitted of courſe to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend the ſaid error, ſlip, or miſtaking, paying to the Defendant, or his At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tourney for his uſe coſts as the ſixe Clarkes not towards the cauſe ſhall thinke fit, but if the Plaintife in that time doe not amend or alter it, then if the Defendant doe nothing therein within a week following, by getting it ruled or referred, it ſhall be diſallowed of courſe without any motion as put in for delay, and the Defendant ſhall pay ordinary coſts: but if the Plaintife not amending the ſame as aforeſaid, it bee ruled againſt him upon Reference, or otherwiſe, he ſhall pay the ordinarie coſts.</p>
                  <p n="16">
                     <pb n="144" facs="tcp:66379:76"/>16. When a Plaintife excepteth to a Defendants anſwer, he ſhall ſet down his exceptions in writing, and deliver it to the Councell whoſe hand is to the anſwer, or to the Defendants Attorney in Court, and if the Defendants doe within a weeke ſatisfie the Plaintife of the invalidity of his exceptions, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend the anſwer in the ſame time, or agree with the Plaintife, or his Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, or Sollicitor to amend it by ſuch a time as ſhall be agreed on betweene them, and doe amend it accordingly without putting the Plaintife to obtain a Reference, or make any motion ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts, then the Defendant ſhall pay no coſts, and if any Plaintife ſhall preſſe and procure a Reference within this time, or before this courſe taken, the Reference ſhall be void, as obtain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed ſurreptitiouſly; But if the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant doe neither ſatisfie the Plaintife, nor amend his anſwer in manner afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, then if upon Reference or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe his anſwer be ruled inſufficient, he ſhall pay coſts according to the courſe of the Court.</p>
                  <p n="17">17. The Maſters of the Court ſhall prefixe convenient, but not overlong daies for hearing ſuch matters as are referred to them, and at the times pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fixed ſhall proceed without admitting any fained or dilatorie excuſes, eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:66379:76"/>
that Councell are otherwiſe im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed, or cannot attend, or are not inſtructed (there having been notice and time enough allowed, or the like, and after the daies ſhall ſpeedily ſend in their Reports for the caſe of the Clients attendance, which cannot but draw great charge.</p>
                  <p n="18">18. If the Caſe be ſuch as the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter cannot proceed in the abſence of either party, or his Counſell without juſt cauſe abſenting, the Maſter is pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſently to certifie the Court of the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault, that the defaulters may be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed by Commitment, Coſts, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe, as the cauſe ſhall merit, and if the Maſter doe uſe or willingly ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit any groſſe delay, the Reference is to be removed, and the Maſter rebuked by the Court.</p>
                  <p n="19">19. The Maſters of the Court are not upon the importunity of Councell, or Clients to make ſpeciall Certificates of matters wherein the Court expects an opinion from them, nor are to doe it, but where their owne judgements in reſpect of difficulty leadeth them to it, it occaſioning for the moſt part a need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe trouble to the Court, and both de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lay and expence to the party.</p>
                  <p n="20">20. No Reference ſhall be to a Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter whether an injunction ſhall bee granted or not, but the ſame to paſſe
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:66379:77"/>
upon the opinion and judgement of the Court, but if the Court thinke the matter informed ſufficient for an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction, but is doubtfull of the truth any point of the information: The Court when it cannot otherwiſe be fitly done, may be certified thereof by a Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter who is then to certifie not only whether the information be in ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance true, but if there appeare other matter to confeſſe and avoid, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe ballance that information he muſt not conceale it, but give the Court a cleare and true information.</p>
                  <p n="21">21. No References are to be made either to Maſters, or others (unleſſe it be by aſſent on both ſides) to heare and determine the cauſe upon all the proofes or otherwiſe; but when the Court hath heard it, and reduced it to particular points, ſpecially if theſe points have relation to Accompts, or matter of that nature, the Court may fitly leave ſuch to be reduced to cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainty by a Maſter.</p>
                  <p n="22">22. The Regiſter ſhall within tenne daies after the end of every Term cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie to the Lord Keeper what Referen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces depend in the hand of any Maſter, and how long they have depended, that if any of them have depended overlong, the Court may require an account thereof from the Maſter, and
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:66379:77"/>
quicken him to a ſpeedy diſpatch.</p>
                  <p n="23">23. When a Maſter certifieth the ſufficiency or inſufficiency of an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, Plea, or Demurrer, if either par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty reſt not in the Report, but trouble the Court to determine it, if the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters Report be confirmed, he that op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſeth it ſhall not pay double coſts.</p>
                  <p n="24">24. Where the Maſters of the Court doe ſometime by way of inducement fill a leafe or two of the beginning of their Reports, and ſometimes more with a long and particular recitall of the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verall points of the orders of Refe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence, they ſhall forbeare ſuch iterati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, the ſame appearing ſufficiently in the orders, and without any other re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petition then thus, According to an or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, or by direction of an order of ſuch a date, ſhall fall directly into the mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of their Report, ſetting downe the ſame clearely, but as briefly as they can, for the eaſe both of the Court, and the parties.</p>
                  <p n="25">25. That Counſellors be carefull what motions they make, and eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly that they move not for any thing which may be had of courſe without motion, nor for ſuch thing as cannot be granted, as being a conſtant rule of the Court or common Juſtice, nor yet for ſuch things, as being granted, ſerve for little or no purpoſe, And before
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:66379:78"/>
they move the Court, they be ſure to be well informed and inſtructed, leſt i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the orders obtained by them upon miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>information to be after avoided, their Clients or themſelves bee deſervedly puniſhed with coſts, or otherwiſe.</p>
                  <p n="26">26. When orders be made, eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly if it be upon hearing of Councell on both ſides, or after day to ſhew cauſe given, and none ſhewed there being a timely notice, both ſides are to reſt in it without troubling the Court with new motions to croſſe it, unleſſe the Counſellour that moves it, be ſure that the matter he hath to croſſe it be weigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and important, and will be well proved upon the motion, ſuch as ſhall doe the contrary are to be puniſhed with good coſts, and otherwiſe, as the Court ſhall finde cauſe.</p>
                  <p n="27">27. That no Counſellour put his hand to a Bill, Anſwer, or other plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, unleſſe it be drawne by himſelfe, or at leaſt peruſed by himſelfe in the paper draught before it be ingroſſed, and that the Counſellour that puts his hand to any ſuch, ſhall be anſwerable for all things therein, either againſt theſe orders or any other the orders or rules of the Court, except only ſuch things as are not to be miſliked but for untruth, for which the Client if he in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed it, or ſuch as cauſed it to be put
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:66379:78"/>
in without his warrant or information, ſhall be anſwerable.</p>
                  <p n="28">28. If any Counſellours ſhall pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſume to move for one in <hi>forma pauperis</hi> that is not ſo admitted, and ſhall under that pretence move a ſecond motion, the Regiſter ſhall enter neither of his orders, but ſhall within foure daies ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaint the Lord Keeper, or Maſter of the Rolls with the abuſe, that he that did it may be condignely puniſhed.</p>
                  <p n="29">29. Counſellours before they take on them to informe by motion, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe that any thing is contained in the Bill, Anſwers, Pleadings, Proofes pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed, or in any Deeds or Records, ought to be carefull in peruſing the ſame themſelves, and not to reſt upon the information of the Client, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> his Sollicitor, who cannot ſo well judge of them, and whoſe part it is to produce thoſe things unto the Counſellours, but it is the Counſellours part to direct how far forth the ſame are to be preſſed or urged to the Count, and they are to ſuſtaine the blame or puniſhment, if either wittingly or negligently, for want of reading or peruſing, they a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſe the Court therein.</p>
                  <p n="30">30. For avoiding a multitude of idle petitions drawne by perſons altogether ignorant of the orders and courſe of the Court, or the true ſtate of the petitio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:66379:79"/>
buſineſſe that petitions before they be preſented to the Lord Keeper, or the Maſter of the Rolls be ſhewed to that ſix Clarke, who is the petitioners Attourney in Court, or to his, and by him approved and ſubſcribed, for which no Fee ſhall be taken, and this is not to be underſtood of petitions adviſed and ſigned by Councell, nor petitions containing any matter of complaint againſt the Attourney or his under-Clarke.</p>
                  <p n="31">31. All the Clarkes of this Court, in copying, ingroſſing, inrolling, or other writing, ſhall doe the ſame fairely, or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derly, and Clark-like, not doing it waſtfully, nor in leſſe Skins or Rolls of parchment, or leaves of Paper then ought to be, thereby increaſing their owne and their Maſters profit, or the Subjects charge, and if the Maſter of the Office upon complaint to him, doe not doe right therein, the Lord Keeper, or the Maſter of the Rolls ſhall puniſh both the Maſter and the Clarke, and yeeld recompence to the complainant upon complaint made to either of them, within two Termes after the offence done.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>Novemb. 17. 1635.</date>
                     </dateline>
                     <signed>Tho: Coventry C. S.</signed>
                     <signed>Iul: Caeſar.</signed>
                  </closer>
                  <pb facs="tcp:66379:79"/>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>
